<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruha Healing</title>
    <link>https://ruhahealing.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ruhahealing.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ruha Healing</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ruhahealing.com/images/logo_huca68e505b6efdf45301ea8190ea96ded_9152_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Ruha Healing</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mantras in Kundalini Yoga</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/mantras-in-kundalini-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/mantras-in-kundalini-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As in no other form of yoga, Kundalini Yoga uses a wide variety of mantras again and again. The participants are then invited to chant the mantras (alternatively humming, speaking or thinking - but ideally chanting) and thus awaken a very special power: the &lt;strong&gt;Naad&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-naad-mean&#34;&gt;What does Naad mean?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Naad is the &lt;strong&gt;inherent being of every sound&lt;/strong&gt;, or the &lt;strong&gt;sound current&lt;/strong&gt;. Through the harmony in the vibration you can experience &lt;strong&gt;infinity&lt;/strong&gt; and feel it within you. Every sound influences you and changes your state. By speaking or chanting positively affirmed mantras, you allow your soul to &lt;strong&gt;access the higher energies&lt;/strong&gt; and an &lt;strong&gt;elevated state of consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-mantra-mean&#34;&gt;What does mantra mean?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, the word &lt;em&gt;mantra&lt;/em&gt; comes from Sanskrit and is translated as &lt;em&gt;sacred syllable/word/verse&lt;/em&gt;. In yoga, a mantra is spoken of as the &lt;strong&gt;creative projection of the mind&lt;/strong&gt;.  Through the generated sound or sound current and the vibration, a mantra triggers a &lt;strong&gt;specific, targeted effect&lt;/strong&gt; on you and your chakras. Each mantra brings its own sound and thus specific energy, which can then affect you. You can therefore also use mantras in a very specific way to &lt;strong&gt;create a certain effect&lt;/strong&gt;. This in turn allows you to &lt;strong&gt;control and direct your mind more consciously&lt;/strong&gt;. Each mantra has a positive effect on you and supports you in your individual processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-language-of-mantras&#34;&gt;The language of mantras&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mantras used in Kundalini Yoga are primarily from &lt;strong&gt;Gurmukhi&lt;/strong&gt;, a sacred Indian language, and thus are usually not directly translatable for us. A few Kundalini Yoga mantras are also in &lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;. You can find out for all mantras their translation as well as meaning or inherent power in books or online. However, for the effect of the mantras you do not need to understand its words and their meaning, because the mantra works anyway. Often you will have a sense of it and can trust it when you feel drawn to a particular mantra - perhaps initially for no apparent reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice: &lt;strong&gt;Trust your intuition&lt;/strong&gt; and let it guide you &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;speciality-in-kundalini-yoga&#34;&gt;Speciality in Kundalini Yoga&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially in Kundalini Yoga mantras attain a special position and have a much &lt;strong&gt;higher priority&lt;/strong&gt; compared to other yoga styles. The power of mantras is an &lt;strong&gt;important part&lt;/strong&gt; of Kundalini Yoga and therefore indispensable.
Right at the &lt;strong&gt;beginning&lt;/strong&gt; of a Kundalini Yoga session, two well-known mantras are chanted - first the Adi Mantra, which is usually followed by the Mangala Charan Protective Mantra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;adi-mantra--translation&#34;&gt;Adi Mantra &amp;amp; Translation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONG NAMO GURU DEV NAMO
&lt;em&gt;(I salute the energy that leads me from darkness to light).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mangala-charan-mantra&#34;&gt;Mangala Charan Mantra&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AD GURE NAMEH
&lt;em&gt;(I salute the energy that is always there.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JUGAD GURE NAMEH
&lt;em&gt;(I salute the energy through all the ages.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SAT GURE NAMEH
&lt;em&gt;(I salute the true energy.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIRI GURU DEV-E NAMEH
&lt;em&gt;(I salute the all-encompassing energy.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To conclude the yoga class, the song &lt;em&gt;May the long time sun&lt;/em&gt; is classically sung with 3 final long &amp;ldquo;Sat Nam&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;may-the-long-time-sun&#34;&gt;May the long time sun&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MAY THE LONG TIME SUN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SHINE UPON YOU&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALL LOVE SURROUND YOU&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AND THE PURE LIGHT WITHIN YOU&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GUIDE YOUR WAY ON&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, each yoga session has a &lt;strong&gt;clear framework&lt;/strong&gt; and also triggers trust through this &lt;strong&gt;recurring ritual&lt;/strong&gt; of mantra singing. In addition, within the yoga session, (short) mantras are regularly used - such as &lt;em&gt;Har&lt;/em&gt; (which means &lt;em&gt;creative creativity&lt;/em&gt;). These are &lt;strong&gt;often related to a movement&lt;/strong&gt;. Especially the mantra &lt;em&gt;Sat Nam&lt;/em&gt; is offered again and again for the students to let it resonate as a mantra in their mind during the individual exercises. Often the mantra is then &lt;strong&gt;combined with the breath&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. inhale &lt;em&gt;Sat&lt;/em&gt;, exhale &lt;em&gt;Nam&lt;/em&gt;. This tightens the focus of the student. Sat Nam can be translated as &lt;em&gt;true identity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;meditation--mantra&#34;&gt;Meditation &amp;amp; Mantra&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, there are many meditations that use a mantra. So-called &lt;em&gt;Celestial Communications&lt;/em&gt; use a certain mantra recurrently and &lt;strong&gt;connect the words with certain body movements&lt;/strong&gt;. Here the use of creativity is definitely allowed, so that different movements can be used in harmony with the mantra. This form of &lt;strong&gt;meditation in movement&lt;/strong&gt; is something very special and unique, which you will find in this form in the yoga world only in Kundalini Yoga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you like to get in touch with mantras and practice some Kundalini Yoga? Then feel welcome to join my yoga classes at any time. As a small gift from me, the first yoga session is free of charge, so you can join without any pressure. Feel free to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/#next_sessions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sign up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for it and dive into this fascinating Kundalini Yoga world of mantras and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have fun exploring the world of mantras &amp;amp; more. 🎶&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The moon points</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-moon-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-moon-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The topic, which I would like to bring closer to you today, is mainly aimed at &lt;strong&gt;women&lt;/strong&gt;. But why? Women have eleven moon points and are &lt;strong&gt;strongly influenced&lt;/strong&gt; by them, while men have only one moon point. Nevertheless, the article is also exciting for men, in order to be able to classify and &lt;strong&gt;understand&lt;/strong&gt; the women in their life and environment a little better. Haven&amp;rsquo;t men always wanted to understand women? 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;moon-points---what-is-that&#34;&gt;Moon points - what is that?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moon points are &lt;strong&gt;areas of the body that react to the moon energy&lt;/strong&gt;. These lunar energies affect your &lt;strong&gt;emotional balance&lt;/strong&gt;, that is, your mood.
The moon influences our earth, the tides, but also the growth of plants and even hair, as well as the rhythms of animals and the cycle of women. So the moon&amp;rsquo;s sphere of influence is quite massive, and we can - indeed, should - take advantage of our knowledge of it. After all, it can help us to understand some connections in a new way and find a new approach especially in our &lt;strong&gt;interaction&lt;/strong&gt; with other people, ourselves and especially women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;moon-point-of-the-man&#34;&gt;Moon point of the man&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As already mentioned, only &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; moon point is found in men. This is located on the &lt;strong&gt;chin&lt;/strong&gt;. If a man wears a &lt;strong&gt;beard&lt;/strong&gt; on this spot, solar energy can be absorbed through it and consequently the influence of the moon can be neutralized. Also, it is in the nature of the man to gain the greater influence through the energy of the &lt;strong&gt;sun&lt;/strong&gt;. Accordingly, the influence of the moon in men is much less than in women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;moon-points-of-the-woman&#34;&gt;Moon points of the woman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women, on the other hand, have &lt;strong&gt;eleven&lt;/strong&gt; moon points that influence their emotional experience. Each moon point controls different aspects of &lt;strong&gt;personality&lt;/strong&gt;. Moon energy also flows into women through the chin and is then transmitted to the moon points. About &lt;strong&gt;every 2.5 days&lt;/strong&gt; a woman&amp;rsquo;s moon point changes, which means that every 2.5 days a different moon point is supplied with moon energy and is therefore present. Thus, a cycle through all eleven moon points lasts about &lt;strong&gt;28 days&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at all eleven moon points and their respective effects on the woman one after the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-hairline&#34;&gt;1 Hairline&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days are characterized by the qualities of &lt;strong&gt;centeredness, self-confidence, open-mindedness, clarity, strength&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;decisiveness&lt;/strong&gt;. You are completely and most of all yourself, which means you &lt;strong&gt;know who you are and what you want&lt;/strong&gt;. You are at your best at this time. You succeed in neutral communication and feel light. This is a &lt;strong&gt;good time to make important decisions&lt;/strong&gt; in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-eyebrows&#34;&gt;2 Eyebrows&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This moon point brings you &lt;strong&gt;flourishing ideas, fantasies, imagination and expansion of consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a good time to express your &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt; and sow new ideas, however, it is not the best time to make decisions as there is a danger of getting in your own way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-cheeks&#34;&gt;3 Cheeks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cheeks harbor &lt;strong&gt;powerful energies&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;very irritable mood&lt;/strong&gt;. You are &lt;strong&gt;very emotional&lt;/strong&gt; and out of control. You are bothered by the smallest things. There is a danger that you will look for &lt;strong&gt;strife and resistance&lt;/strong&gt;. You can balance this tendency through &lt;strong&gt;meditation&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;conscious communication&lt;/strong&gt;. In this phase, &lt;strong&gt;discipline&lt;/strong&gt; is necessary to keep yourself in check. Eating well and drinking a lot is also helpful. Use these days rather for &lt;strong&gt;retreat&lt;/strong&gt; and for some &lt;strong&gt;time with yourself&lt;/strong&gt; and best do not make any important decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-lips&#34;&gt;4 Lips&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, all of a sudden you are totally &lt;strong&gt;talkative&lt;/strong&gt;. Your &lt;strong&gt;communication goes to extremes&lt;/strong&gt; - it&amp;rsquo;s either effective, uplifting and positive, or sharp-tongued, destructive and annoying. Find your &lt;strong&gt;balance&lt;/strong&gt; and do things that are good for you, such as &lt;strong&gt;meditation&lt;/strong&gt;. Rely on your intuition and feel whether the tendency in you is more negative or positive, and depending on the situation, it is better to stay calm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-earlobes&#34;&gt;5 Earlobes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your earlobes rule the energies, it means &lt;strong&gt;constant questioning and discussion of values&lt;/strong&gt; for you. You are &lt;strong&gt;very analytical&lt;/strong&gt; with a tendency to be highly &lt;strong&gt;self-critical&lt;/strong&gt;. This is not a good time to make final decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;6-neck&#34;&gt;6 Neck&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neck represents a desire for &lt;strong&gt;sensuality&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;romance&lt;/strong&gt; and brings to life your &lt;strong&gt;need for touch through skin contact, music, romantic books and movies&lt;/strong&gt;. You are &lt;strong&gt;loving, gentle, kind&lt;/strong&gt;, and also a &lt;strong&gt;risk taker&lt;/strong&gt;. You have an enchanted daily life through little things that make you happy. &lt;strong&gt;Self-love&lt;/strong&gt; is especially easy for you now. It is important to you to take time for yourself. You also like to &lt;strong&gt;flirt&lt;/strong&gt; and have a &lt;strong&gt;desire for new things&lt;/strong&gt;. These days are also not a good time to make important decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;7-breasts&#34;&gt;7 Breasts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you feel a great deal of &lt;strong&gt;compassion&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;like to give&lt;/strong&gt; to your fellow man. You have a &lt;strong&gt;strong social commitment&lt;/strong&gt; and a feeling of +*overflowing love**. These days you are very anchored in your &lt;strong&gt;heart&lt;/strong&gt;. Your longing for &lt;strong&gt;intimacy&lt;/strong&gt; is being pursued and you feel connected to the big whole. However, &lt;strong&gt;saying no is difficult&lt;/strong&gt; for you, so this is also not a good time for personal as well as business decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;8-belly-button&#34;&gt;8 Belly Button&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On these days you feel a &lt;strong&gt;strong insecurity and instability&lt;/strong&gt;. You succeed only little, your &lt;strong&gt;concentration is weaker&lt;/strong&gt;. You lack the desire to socialize, so you &lt;strong&gt;tend to withdraw&lt;/strong&gt;. Right now you are &lt;strong&gt;very vulnerable&lt;/strong&gt; - especially to criticism. You have a tendency to compensate for your insecurity by being &lt;strong&gt;aggressive&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, accept the help of others instead of playing the strong woman when you actually feel weak. &lt;strong&gt;Listen to your inner self and relax when you need it.&lt;/strong&gt; Exercises to &lt;strong&gt;strengthen your navel&lt;/strong&gt; will help you and &lt;strong&gt;chanting&lt;/strong&gt; is also good. Currently is not a good time for discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;9-thighs&#34;&gt;9 Thighs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your presence is characterized by &lt;strong&gt;steadfastness&lt;/strong&gt; and you are in the process of wanting to affirm and confirm everything. Others sense your great &lt;strong&gt;persistence&lt;/strong&gt; and that you strongly hold and assert your own opinions. You are &lt;strong&gt;full of energy, productive, self-reliant&lt;/strong&gt; and able to get things done with ease. Finally, a &lt;strong&gt;good time to make decisions&lt;/strong&gt; has arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;10-clitoris&#34;&gt;10 Clitoris&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This moon point awakens your need for &lt;strong&gt;wider social circles&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;expanding contacts&lt;/strong&gt;. You are &lt;strong&gt;talkative&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;charming, meeting friends&lt;/strong&gt; and generally enjoying going out. &lt;strong&gt;Social interaction&lt;/strong&gt; delights and fulfills you. This is a good time to take leadership and &lt;strong&gt;organize&lt;/strong&gt; things. But be careful not to ostracize the other people around you too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;11-vagina&#34;&gt;11 Vagina&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your vagina represents your need for &lt;strong&gt;closeness&lt;/strong&gt; in the narrower sense (partner, family and friends). &lt;strong&gt;Deep intimacy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;companionship&lt;/strong&gt; are important to you. However, you may also have a feeling of &lt;strong&gt;emptiness&lt;/strong&gt; and a need to be &lt;strong&gt;alone&lt;/strong&gt;. If so, take some time off and enjoy &lt;strong&gt;meditating&lt;/strong&gt;. Connect with the divine and your stillness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-how-do-you-deal-with-this-knowledge-now-&#34;&gt;And how do you deal with this knowledge now? 🌙&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know the sequence of your moon points, you can &lt;strong&gt;understand yourself much better&lt;/strong&gt; and also your partner, family and friends can benefit from this knowledge. The good thing is, if you first know the sequence of your moon points, because this &lt;strong&gt;sequence always stays the same&lt;/strong&gt; - unless you experience an enormous shock or trauma. To figure out the sequence, you can, for example, &lt;strong&gt;write down in your calendar every day how you feel and which moon point that might correspond to&lt;/strong&gt;. Just rely on your feeling and &lt;strong&gt;trust your intuition&lt;/strong&gt;. Through &lt;strong&gt;conscious observation&lt;/strong&gt;, you will be able to figure out your moon point progression well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also use &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga techniques&lt;/strong&gt; to stimulate your moon points. In general, &lt;strong&gt;chanting mantras&lt;/strong&gt; is an excellent technique for this. You can also practice the &lt;strong&gt;Kirtan Kriya while lying down to balance your moon points&lt;/strong&gt;. To do this, lie on your belly and rest your chin on the floor. Your arms are on the sides of your body with your palms facing up. With your fingers, form the sequence familiar from Kirtan Kriya along with the &amp;ldquo;Sa Ta Na Ma&amp;rdquo; mantra. You can do this meditation for 3 - 31 minutes. Feel free to do it for 40 days at a time to get a long term effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;i-wish-you-much-joy-in-exploring-your-moon-points&#34;&gt;I wish you much joy in exploring your moon points!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sat-nam-&#34;&gt;Sat Nam 🙏&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did You Know You Have an Eighth Chakra?</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/eighth-chakra-aura-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/eighth-chakra-aura-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that in the teachings of Kundalini Yoga the aura is also called the Eighth Chakra? Surely you’ve heard the term aura before and know roughly what it’s all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, let’s dive a little deeper into the knowledge of auras from the perspective of Kundalini Yoga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-your-aura-and-how-does-it-act-as-your-eighth-chakra&#34;&gt;What Is Your Aura? And How Does It Act as Your Eighth Chakra?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many chakra theories and illustrations do not include the aura as the Eighth Chakra. In Kundalini Yoga, however, the aura plays as significant a role as any of the other seven major chakras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aura is located outside your body. It is related to your radiance. In terms of color, the aura is represented as white and is located in the electromagnetic field of your body.
&lt;strong&gt;In the Eighth Chakra, the effects of all other chakras are brought together.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not associated with any of the elements, but simply with the feeling of being. The aura gives you the space for yourself and fills it with yourself. Essentially, your aura is your presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Eighth Chakra, the effects of all other chakras are brought together. The aura also represents the power of the energy shell that surrounds all the other seven chakras, a kind of ambient field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the specific energy of the aura, the universal flow of energy is fixed. You can feel a deep connection within you through the power of your aura as it weaves you into the entire universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every person has an aura, and they can be anywhere from three to nine feet tall. Some people can even see the aura of others, and it’s possible to strengthen this ability in yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read the &lt;strong&gt;full article&lt;/strong&gt; on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yogiapproved.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;YogiApproved&lt;/a&gt;, click &lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yogiapproved.com/om/eighth-chakra-aura/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding KRIYA</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/understanding_kriya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/understanding_kriya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;term-kriya&#34;&gt;Term Kriya&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;strong&gt;Kriya&lt;/strong&gt; can be translated as &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;action&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. In Kundalini Yoga, it usually means a complete series of exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This specific action is seen as the &lt;strong&gt;origin&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;seed&lt;/strong&gt;, so to speak, from which &lt;strong&gt;something much greater can blossom&lt;/strong&gt;. This image already shows how much power there is in a Kriya. Practicing a Kriya can enable you to do many things, it makes you grow and sooner or later changes your reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;kriya-in-the-context-of-kundalini-yoga&#34;&gt;Kriya in the context of Kundalini Yoga&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As already mentioned, the Kriya in Kundalini Yoga is a &lt;strong&gt;whole series of exercises&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. often a sequence of specific postures as well as breathing and sound. The individual specific Kriyas represent a respective &lt;strong&gt;unity&lt;/strong&gt; and stand for themselves. Behind each Kriya is a &lt;strong&gt;goal&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;direction&lt;/strong&gt;, which you can ideally engage in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single Kriya in Kundalini Yoga is often &lt;strong&gt;repeated&lt;/strong&gt; over several days, weeks or even months. In this way, you can repeat each Kriya regularly to &lt;strong&gt;explore the depth&lt;/strong&gt; that lies within the Kriya and eventually master it. In doing so, you can open up to new levels of &lt;strong&gt;consciousness of your Self&lt;/strong&gt; and reach a certain state. Each Kriya is balanced in itself and should be practiced exactly as it is written. If you &lt;strong&gt;strictly follow the instructions&lt;/strong&gt; that each Kriya implies, you will be able to achieve the desired goal of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-a-kriya-do-to-you&#34;&gt;What does a Kriya do to you?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feeling the depth and meaning of the Kriya through your yoga practice is one thing. The next is that you should also be aware of the &lt;strong&gt;magnitude&lt;/strong&gt; beyond that. Experiencing Kriyas in Kundalini Yoga can also affect your life in general. It is quite possible that you will become more and more &lt;strong&gt;in harmony&lt;/strong&gt;, your life will experience &lt;strong&gt;wholeness&lt;/strong&gt; and your actions will experience &lt;strong&gt;appropriateness&lt;/strong&gt; as you may never have felt before. Through this feeling and anchoring in your Self, &lt;strong&gt;grace&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;dignity&lt;/strong&gt; eventually emerge throughout your body. You are powerful and endowed with the ability to &lt;strong&gt;accomplish things&lt;/strong&gt;, to &lt;strong&gt;use actions appropriately&lt;/strong&gt; - timeless and timely at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some postures in Kundalini Yoga may feel uncomfortable to you and others may feel very pleasant. Everyone feels the effects of each posture &lt;strong&gt;individually&lt;/strong&gt;, because this is also related to your &lt;strong&gt;previous experiences&lt;/strong&gt; and of course these are not congruent for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, you can use Kundalini Yoga as a &lt;strong&gt;tool for self-diagnosis&lt;/strong&gt;: Your sensations and feelings during the postures, the Kriya, can give you information about the state of your body, your muscles and glands, and your emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central to Kundalini Yoga practice is your &lt;strong&gt;devotion&lt;/strong&gt;. When you surrender to a Kriya to the highest degree possible, you are most likely to feel the effects of it within you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel invited&lt;/strong&gt; to practice a Kriya and experience what it means to engage in this specific sequence of actions. In my following 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjR4h8QUBW_gUnXkfbEdKQA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; video - a recording of my live session - I guide you through the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nabhi Kriya for Prana and Apana&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. This works on your life energy (Prana) and your energy to let go things (Apana). Both energies are important for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get involved&lt;/strong&gt; and have this &lt;strong&gt;experience with yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. How do you feel afterwards? &lt;strong&gt;Feel exactly inside yourself&lt;/strong&gt;, use this opportunity and above all: be &lt;strong&gt;honest&lt;/strong&gt; with yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be &lt;strong&gt;YOUR chance&lt;/strong&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s up to you if you take it&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;660&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PE9Ip6QjrSc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it feels right, &lt;strong&gt;continue!&lt;/strong&gt; Practice this Kriya again tomorrow, in a few days or make another video. And if you want more, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/#next_sessions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sign up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for my &lt;strong&gt;regular online live Yoga sessions&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to welcome you there and guide you on your path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sat Nam!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get to know your mind</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/get-to-know-your-mind/index.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/get-to-know-your-mind/index.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;rsquo;s look at what exactly is behind your mind. Do you have any idea about it? Your mind is a &lt;strong&gt;complex entity&lt;/strong&gt; and governs you in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-mind-&#34;&gt;The Mind 🤯&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your mind &lt;strong&gt;serves your soul&lt;/strong&gt; and produces many more thoughts than you could ever process. It is &lt;strong&gt;automatic, always active&lt;/strong&gt;, and almost overwhelms you with thoughts. It is your mind that thinks instead of you. There are also thoughts that do not support your true self, what you are. In short, the mind brings with it its pitfalls, so it is good to &lt;strong&gt;understand&lt;/strong&gt; it all the more and use it to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important characteristic of the mind is its &lt;strong&gt;urge to polarize&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that it prefers to sort everything into good and bad, positive and negative. Thus, your mind is always looking for &lt;strong&gt;contrasts&lt;/strong&gt; in order to be able to classify things. And this works best through constant movement, so to speak always on the search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can understand your mind as its &lt;strong&gt;own structure, process or current&lt;/strong&gt;, which you can &lt;strong&gt;observe&lt;/strong&gt; yourself and finally also &lt;strong&gt;change&lt;/strong&gt;. You can achieve changes, for example, through your own thoughts, conscious breathing or meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, it is important that you &lt;strong&gt;understand&lt;/strong&gt; the structure of your mind itself and discover &lt;strong&gt;thought origins&lt;/strong&gt; in order to finally decide for yourself which thoughts are in accordance with and correspond to your &lt;strong&gt;true self&lt;/strong&gt;. By clearly perceiving your thoughts, you can orient yourself to your &lt;strong&gt;soul&lt;/strong&gt; and consciously follow its path. Consequently, you will also be able to perceive an awakening of your &lt;strong&gt;intuition&lt;/strong&gt;, which will support you in living out your &lt;strong&gt;destiny&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
All this is a complex process, because to observe your mind you need your mind, which in turn seems incredibly strong and almost unpredictable. Techniques to control your mind are mainly &lt;strong&gt;meditations, breath control&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;mantras&lt;/strong&gt;. Through these you can find a certain &lt;strong&gt;zero point&lt;/strong&gt;, a place where your mind is still. There is &lt;strong&gt;calmness&lt;/strong&gt; there &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this maelstrom and labyrinth of thoughts about thoughts and the desire to control them, it can become exhausting to stay with it and to deal with your own thought structures. To understand this a bit more, the &lt;strong&gt;three aspects of the mind&lt;/strong&gt; are also important: Your mind is namely divided into &lt;strong&gt;negative, positive and neutral&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-negative-mind-&#34;&gt;The negative mind ➖&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negative mind may sound negative to you at first, but it is not per se. Your negative mind is just as important as your positive and neutral mind and all 3 aspects are present in you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What exactly does it mean that a part of your mind is negative? The negative mind is also called the &lt;strong&gt;protective mind&lt;/strong&gt;, which describes its relevance quite well. It serves you to protect you from &lt;strong&gt;danger&lt;/strong&gt;, so that you simply &lt;strong&gt;survive&lt;/strong&gt;. It lays its protective hand over everything that could threaten, disturb or destroy you. Thus its motto is rather &lt;strong&gt;negation&lt;/strong&gt;. Thereby the protecting mind mainly refers to past experiences and wants to help you e.g. by a &lt;strong&gt;no-signal&lt;/strong&gt; that you do not get involved in a certain thing, because the mind has internalized due to made experiences that this will not be good for you. The main motivation of this mechanism is pure protection and to preserve the high good of life. At the same time, your negative mind is mainly connected to your &lt;strong&gt;subconscious mind&lt;/strong&gt;.
Also, inherent in this aspect of your mind is a &lt;strong&gt;deep longing for belonging&lt;/strong&gt;. The highest form of this connection you can make is with &lt;strong&gt;your higher self&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sat Nam!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-positive-mind-&#34;&gt;The positive mind ➕&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you already know, your mind is not only negative, but also positive oriented. These two aspects seem like two opposite ends. But are they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The positive mind is the &lt;strong&gt;expansive&lt;/strong&gt; part of your mind. It is in search of &lt;strong&gt;pleasure&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;fulfillment&lt;/strong&gt;. In contrast to the reactive negative mind, the positive mind is &lt;strong&gt;active, risk-taking&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;constructive&lt;/strong&gt;. It rather sends &lt;strong&gt;yes-messages&lt;/strong&gt; and encourages you to do things, freely according to the motto &amp;ldquo;Come what may&amp;rdquo; or &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everything is possible&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. In this way, the expansive mind strengthens your thoughts and tempts you into a constant saying yes, if it is very pronounced. It thus gives you a &lt;strong&gt;strong will&lt;/strong&gt; and generates &lt;strong&gt;strong, direct communication&lt;/strong&gt;. It is also characterized by expansion and the ability to let resources in. There is a strong reference to the &lt;strong&gt;future&lt;/strong&gt;, behind which there is certainly a certain curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it becomes clear that the two aspects negative and positive are relatively opposed to each other, since they pursue completely different goals and function fundamentally differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-neutral-mind-&#34;&gt;The neutral mind 🙏&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can you combine both influences, positive and negative, and make decisions? For this you have your neutral mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part is also called &lt;strong&gt;meditative mind&lt;/strong&gt;. It has the power to &lt;strong&gt;judge&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;assess&lt;/strong&gt;. It does not pursue its own goal and is not attached to your reality. It has the ability to observe the actions of negative and positive mind, without joining one part directly. It can &lt;strong&gt;decide&lt;/strong&gt; for you which direction is better for you - and that within &lt;strong&gt;9 seconds&lt;/strong&gt;. Relevant for the meditative mind is only your &lt;strong&gt;higher self&lt;/strong&gt;, with which it is connected. However, this connection can be more or less strong. It is important to train and &lt;strong&gt;strengthen&lt;/strong&gt; this aspect of your mind so that you can live your life in the greatest possible harmony with your higher self and ultimately your &lt;strong&gt;destiny&lt;/strong&gt;. Your view will become more &lt;strong&gt;intuitive&lt;/strong&gt; and you will be able to touch your &lt;strong&gt;soul&lt;/strong&gt;. Thus, the neutral mind is characterized by &lt;strong&gt;consciousness&lt;/strong&gt; and has access to the soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-do-these-insights-into-the-mind-mean-for-you&#34;&gt;What do these insights into the mind mean for you?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As already mentioned, &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; these parts are also present in you. The individual aspects are developed differently in every person. Maybe you have a feeling for it, how the situation is with your mind currently&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically it is the case that &lt;strong&gt;EVERY&lt;/strong&gt; thought is filtered through the negative, positive and neutral mind. Your neutral mind then makes - provided it is developed accordingly - the decision that is best for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through a developed neutral mind you stay &lt;strong&gt;centered, whole&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;together&lt;/strong&gt;. The whole experience can be enjoyed in this way. But this neutral state of mind must first be &lt;strong&gt;developed&lt;/strong&gt;, trained, experienced and refined. After that, any success in life is possible. Through the practice of &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga and meditation&lt;/strong&gt;, you can develop and train your neutral mind and with it the capacity for intelligence, perseverance and &lt;strong&gt;integrity&lt;/strong&gt;. Meditating on a &lt;strong&gt;regular&lt;/strong&gt; basis is one of the most important fundaments for a strong and supporting neutral mind. Finally, with the neutral mind you can establish an intuitive way of seeing as well as &lt;strong&gt;access to your own soul&lt;/strong&gt;. Your actions in this state are dignified and follow your &lt;strong&gt;heart&lt;/strong&gt; as well as your soul. Your own light can penetrate outward and thus &lt;strong&gt;infect other lights&lt;/strong&gt;, other souls. 🔆 Doesn&amp;rsquo;t that sound wonderful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are welcome to join my regular Kundalini Yoga sessions.&lt;/strong&gt; The best way to register for them is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/#next_sessions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, you can also send me an 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ruhahealing@gmail.com?subject=Join%20the%20Kundalini%20Yoga%20sessions&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🎁 As a newcomer, your &lt;strong&gt;first lesson&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;strong&gt;free gift&lt;/strong&gt; from me to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am convinced that the regular practice of Kundalini Yoga strengthens your neutral mind, but also brings other manifold &lt;strong&gt;positive effects&lt;/strong&gt;. In each session there is also a part at the end where we &lt;strong&gt;meditate&lt;/strong&gt;. By meditating again and again, you are also doing something good for your whole system. Thus, a &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga class&lt;/strong&gt; is a wonderful overall package for you to get closer to yourself and to &lt;strong&gt;follow the path of your soul&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wahe Guru!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11-Day Meditation Challenge</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/11-day-meditation-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/11-day-meditation-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meditating has been with me for a couple of years now and over time I have become more and more immersed in this &lt;strong&gt;fascinating&lt;/strong&gt; subject. You can meditate in many different ways - including the &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; way. 😉
But first let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at what exactly it means to meditate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;meaning-of-meditation&#34;&gt;Meaning of meditation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, meditating is a &lt;strong&gt;process&lt;/strong&gt; that enables you to &lt;strong&gt;control and eventually overcome your thought waves&lt;/strong&gt;. Every second your mind produces new thoughts, so you find yourself in a sea of them. By &lt;strong&gt;consciously&lt;/strong&gt; meditating, you can order this sea and bring it to rest. This allows your &lt;strong&gt;soul&lt;/strong&gt; to shine. It can then shape its path, its &lt;strong&gt;destiny&lt;/strong&gt;, in a more focused way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;effects-of-meditating&#34;&gt;Effects of meditating&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else does the act of meditating bring? There is a long list of &lt;strong&gt;positive effects on your system&lt;/strong&gt;. I will present you the most important ones here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development of your neutral mind.&lt;/strong&gt; This is also called the meditative mind. It is important to make decisions in your life as neutral as possible - without positive or negative influences - and aligned with the purpose of your soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased well-being, inner peace, stability and tranquility.&lt;/strong&gt; By controlling your multiple thoughts, you inevitably attain a more peaceful state and radiate more and more tranquility to the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developing your intuition.&lt;/strong&gt; Your intuition has an enormously important power, as it guides you to where your soul wants to go. Unfortunately, many people lose the connection to their own intuition and act increasingly from the mind. A reconnection to as well as expansion of your intuition will come about through regular meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promoting mental clarity, mental awareness and existence in the present.&lt;/strong&gt; Through meditation you will learn to overcome your thoughts. That is, you no longer allow yourself to be so strongly guided by your random thoughts, but take the helm yourself, so to speak. You act more and more consciously and clearly and can thereby perceive yourself and your environment in the here and now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development of the frontal lobe of the anterior brain.&lt;/strong&gt; Here, among other things, the seat of your personality is located, as well as a great connection to your executive functions. Abilities in this area are therefore promoted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive influence on blood pressure, cholesterol level and immune system.&lt;/strong&gt;
The resulting relaxation probably allows narrowed blood vessels to dilate again, so that your blood pressure is lowered. In addition, stress increases your susceptibility to disease because your immune system is weaker. Meditation reduces your perception of stress, which improves the performance of your immune system. Since stress also causes high cholesterol, the process of meditation lowers it as well as blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing the mind.&lt;/strong&gt; By directing your thoughts and letting them pass you by more instead of taking them in, you keep your subconscious mind cleaner. These passing thoughts can&amp;rsquo;t even penetrate your system deeply enough to seek out your subconscious mind. By doing this, you purify your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you see, the activity of meditating - especially &lt;strong&gt;regularly&lt;/strong&gt; - brings many beneficial effects. I can only say: &lt;strong&gt;It is worth it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;types-of-meditation-in-kundalini-yoga&#34;&gt;Types of meditation in Kundalini Yoga&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can meditate in &lt;strong&gt;many different ways&lt;/strong&gt;, which is what Kundalini Yoga likes to do. There are two basic distinctions to make: meditating with or without a &lt;strong&gt;mantra&lt;/strong&gt;. The selection of possible mantras in Kundalini Yoga is relatively large, so you can certainly find a mantra that resonates with you and moves you forward, making your soul shine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, you can meditate not only while &lt;strong&gt;sitting&lt;/strong&gt;, but also while &lt;strong&gt;walking&lt;/strong&gt; or with a &lt;strong&gt;partner&lt;/strong&gt; facing you (then sitting again). There are also meditations in which a deep &lt;strong&gt;gong&lt;/strong&gt; is played or where you use a mala (certain chain of beads that you hold in your hand). In my opinion, especally the gong meditation really has something very magical. Also the so-called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;celestial comunication&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. the connection of mantra and movement, is a form of meditation in Kundalini Yoga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;11-day-meditation-challenge&#34;&gt;11-day meditation challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year, I offered a meditation challenge &lt;strong&gt;online&lt;/strong&gt;. In this challenge we did the &lt;strong&gt;same meditation&lt;/strong&gt; (from Kundalini Yoga) together for &lt;strong&gt;11 days&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;11 minutes&lt;/strong&gt; each day, namely the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Meditation to see the unseen&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. This meditation does not use a mantra, but special arm and hand postures. The left arm is positioned next to the torso and the left hand is brought into Surya Mudra (thumb and ring finger connected). The right arm is extended straight forward with the palm facing upward forming a small cup. You close your eyes in this position and then focus on your moon center, which is your chin.
You can see a picture of the position at the beginning of this post and my video of it right here. 👇&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wM7-2UzCAjw&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most exciting thing is your &lt;strong&gt;own development over these 11 days&lt;/strong&gt; in using meditation. You can feel through repeated practice exactly what the meditation is doing to you, where it is working, how you are taking on the challenge each day and eventually mastering it. After 11 days, you will definitely come out &lt;strong&gt;powerful&lt;/strong&gt; if you have been able to engage in the process of meditating. &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all worth a try!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This meditation challenge really bonded us all together and almost all participants were live every day. So we felt more supported by the group and accepted this challenge &lt;strong&gt;together&lt;/strong&gt;, even if in the end of course everyone was allowed to master the task for themselves.
After 11 days all participants were satisfied and proud of themselves, but at the same time a little sad that the time of meditating together was now over. Of course, everyone can continue to practice with the video I provided, but it is something different to come together live, meditate and feel connected in a special way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have decided to offer a &lt;strong&gt;new 11-day meditation challenge&lt;/strong&gt; to open the space for this again. This time we will practice a &lt;strong&gt;different meditation&lt;/strong&gt;, which again lasts &lt;strong&gt;11 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;. This one also works on your &lt;strong&gt;nervous system&lt;/strong&gt; and strengthens it. In addition, this meditation is said to have a &lt;strong&gt;rejuvenating effect&lt;/strong&gt;. So then, let&amp;rsquo;s go, or what are you still thinking about? 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Facebook_Post.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Take this challenge&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To &lt;strong&gt;join&lt;/strong&gt; the upcoming Kundalini Yoga meditation, you can simply send me an 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ruhahealing@gmail.com?subject=Join%20the%20meditation%20challenge&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or contact me via my &lt;strong&gt;social media channels&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;. 🙏🏽
Then you will receive all the necessary details and after receipt of payment also the access link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am really looking forward to meet you and to start this meditation journey together with you.&lt;/strong&gt; 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sat Nam!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curious about Kundalini Yoga?</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/curious-about-kundalini-yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/curious-about-kundalini-yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga was brought to the West by Yogi Bhajan in 1968.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, this practice was previously only available to selected yogis, and therefore, rather secret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Yogi Bhajan’s goal was to train more teachers instead of gathering a bunch of students around him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since first being introduced to the West, the practice of Kundalini Yoga has become more and more popular and many people have deeply benefited from this unique yoga practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-the-origin-of-kundalini-yoga&#34;&gt;What Is the Origin of Kundalini Yoga?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kundalini Yoga has been practiced for thousands of years. It’s a tradition with a long lineage passed down through many teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It speaks of a &lt;strong&gt;“golden chain”&lt;/strong&gt; as a link to all previous and current teachers. This gives Kundalini Yoga a &lt;strong&gt;deeply spiritual aspect&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is believed that practicing Kundalini Yoga can lead you to your &lt;strong&gt;awakened inner identity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-kundalini-mean&#34;&gt;What Does “Kundalini” Mean?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;em&gt;Kundalini&lt;/em&gt; comes from Sanskrit and is translated as “rolled up; sleeping snake power.” &lt;strong&gt;Every&lt;/strong&gt; human being carries this power, the Kundalini energy or consciousness energy, within him or herself. It is a &lt;strong&gt;creative force&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kundalini is also called the &lt;strong&gt;nerve of the soul&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be awakened. With the awakening of this energy, the yogi attains a &lt;strong&gt;higher level of consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, Kundalini Yoga is also often called the &lt;strong&gt;“yoga of consciousness”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kundalini Yoga represents the &lt;strong&gt;highest technique&lt;/strong&gt; that can awaken your consciousness and your soul. Through this process of awareness, you can unfold your very &lt;strong&gt;own truth&lt;/strong&gt; that naturally lives within you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice is considered a &lt;strong&gt;safe&lt;/strong&gt; way to activate this creative force within you – without losing your hold on the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-happens-in-a-kundalini-yoga-class&#34;&gt;What Happens in a Kundalini Yoga Class?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read the &lt;strong&gt;full article&lt;/strong&gt; on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yogiapproved.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;YogiApproved&lt;/a&gt;, click &lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yogiapproved.com/yoga/kundalini-yoga-101/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The powerful Breath Of Fire</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/breath_of_fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/breath_of_fire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If someone asked me which form of &lt;strong&gt;breathing&lt;/strong&gt; I like best in &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt;, I would definitely answer: &amp;ldquo;The &lt;strong&gt;breath of fire&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;. In the following I will tell you why I think so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you practice yoga, you may have heard about the technique of the breath of fire - also known as &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Agni Pran&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; - or have used it yourself.
Especially in Kundalini Yoga many different breathing techniques are used, which stimulate and support your whole body-mind-soul system in different ways. Today I will deepen with you the insight into the power of the breath of fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-how-does-the-breath-of-fire-work&#34;&gt;🔥 How does the breath of fire work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us start directly with the most important point: the &lt;strong&gt;technique&lt;/strong&gt;. You can best feel all the energy of the breath of fire if you execute this breathing pattern correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit upright in a comfortable sitting position (on your yoga mat or chair/sofa) and stretch your back. Your head will rise and your buttocks will remain firmly rooted to the base of your seat. &lt;strong&gt;Your breath flows through your nose as you breathe in and out.&lt;/strong&gt; Your mouth is closed. First, consciously perceive the flow of your breath. &lt;strong&gt;When breathing in, breathe deeply into your stomach, when breathing out, pull your navel slightly inwards towards your spine&lt;/strong&gt; and press the last air out of your lungs. Connect with the &lt;strong&gt;power of your navel&lt;/strong&gt;. Place one or both hands on your stomach to feel the bulging and contraction directly. Now &lt;strong&gt;slowly increase your breathing speed&lt;/strong&gt; so that your breaths become shorter. Increase the pace until you inhale and exhale about 2-3 times per second, i.e. &lt;strong&gt;2-3 breathing cycles&lt;/strong&gt;. You can perceive that the breath of fire is a &lt;strong&gt;fast, rhythmic and continuous breathing pattern&lt;/strong&gt;. Make sure that inhalation and exhalation are of &lt;strong&gt;equal length&lt;/strong&gt;. During the practice of the breath of fire you will be able to perceive the &lt;strong&gt;movement of your belly&lt;/strong&gt;, because the breath of fire emanates from this area. As you exhale, focus on expelling the air powerfully through your nose by pulling your navel point inward toward your spine. Inhalation is automatic to a certain extent, but you must not remain without attention. This will relax your upper abdominal muscles so that your diaphragm can descend again. Keep your &lt;strong&gt;chest slightly elevated&lt;/strong&gt;. Your chest remains relaxed while you breathe in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explanation &lt;strong&gt;VIDEO&lt;/strong&gt; for you 👇&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/468131528&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-what-effects-does-the-breath-of-fire-have&#34;&gt;🔆 What effects does the breath of fire have?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of &lt;strong&gt;positive effects&lt;/strong&gt; on your entire system from practicing the breath of fire is quite long. If you practice this breathing technique regularly and correctly, you can benefit from these effects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toxins and deposits from your lungs, mucous membranes, blood vessels and other cells are released. The breath of fire has a very cleansing and detoxifying effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your lung capacity expands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your life force or energy (Pran(a)) increases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will experience a strengthening of your nervous system and an increase in its resistance to stress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A balance between your sympathetic and parasympathetic nervous system is established.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your navel chakra is strengthened and thus brings you (more) into your own middle. You become centered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is an increase in your physical stamina.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your actions become more effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your aura experiences an alignment of its subtle psycho-electromagnetic field, which leads to the energization of your blood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any craving for drugs, tobacco or bad food is reduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The oxygen supply to your brain is increased, which supports your concentrated, neutral mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your immune system is strengthened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The synchronization of the biorhythms of your body systems is promoted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You feel warmth coming up inside you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your blood circulation improves and your circulation is strengthened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your fat and cell metabolism and digestion are stimulated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This form of breathing helps against asthma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You reduce anger and rage, become more satisfied and feel more joy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an amazing list of effects. Who would not like to benefit from them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wahe Guru! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;are-there-any-side-effects&#34;&gt;Are there any &amp;ldquo;side effects&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially in the beginning, when you are not that familiar with the breath of fire, you may feel &lt;strong&gt;dizzy&lt;/strong&gt;. Then you should &lt;strong&gt;take a break and return to long, deep breathing&lt;/strong&gt;. If you experience other discomfort or tingling, these are normal symptoms. This is your body showing you that it is getting used to the new breathing technique and that &lt;strong&gt;your nerves are being invigorated&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;focus on your 3rd eye&lt;/strong&gt; can help you to stay focused. In general, such symptoms decrease if you &lt;strong&gt;drink a lot of water&lt;/strong&gt; and change your diet to &lt;strong&gt;light food&lt;/strong&gt;. Depending on what you have been &amp;ldquo;giving&amp;rdquo; to your body so far, toxins may also be released into your body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-limitations-in-the-practice-of-the-breath-of-fire&#34;&gt;🚫 Limitations in the practice of the breath of fire&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also states of your body that restrict you in the practice of the breath of fire.
Several of these primarily affect the &lt;strong&gt;women&lt;/strong&gt; among us.If you are &lt;strong&gt;pregnant&lt;/strong&gt;, you should generally &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; practice breath of fire. Instead, you can use long, deep breathing. During your &lt;strong&gt;menstruation&lt;/strong&gt; it is recommended, especially in the first 1-3 days (depending on the intensity), not to practice breath of fire. However, I would like to deliberately leave this decision to each woman on her own, as each woman experiences the state of her menstruation differently.
If you are a woman going through &lt;strong&gt;menopause&lt;/strong&gt; and are experiencing &lt;strong&gt;hot flashes&lt;/strong&gt;, this is another condition where you should use the breat of fire more critically. The breath of fire heats up your body even more, which can be too much for you at that moment.
If you have &lt;strong&gt;high blood pressure&lt;/strong&gt;, you should also be careful with the breath of fire - this applies to men and women alike - as it can increase your blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is best to &lt;strong&gt;actively feel inside yourself each time&lt;/strong&gt; and then decide if and how intensively you want to practice the breath of fire on that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-can-something-be-done-wrong&#34;&gt;⚡ Can something be done wrong?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. The practice of breath of fire is facing certain difficulties, which I would like to point out to you very clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common breathing mistake is the &lt;strong&gt;paradoxical breath&lt;/strong&gt;. In this case, the stomach goes inwards when breathing in and the chest rises; when breathing out, the stomach goes outwards and the chest lowers again. This pattern is exactly the opposite of how the breath should proceed. This is the way your breath should actually go: When you breathe in, the belly bulges outward and when you breathe out, it moves inward. If you experience paradoxical breathing, it is best to place one hand on your stomach and the other on your chest. In this way you can adjust your breath and consciously and slowly start with the breath of fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may also &lt;strong&gt;use exaggerated abdominal movements&lt;/strong&gt;, similar to a bellows. However, the breath of fire is not bellows breathing. It is created a little higher near the solar plexus. Again, consciously feel inside yourself and perceive the center of the breath of fire for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;strong&gt;attention to the balance between inhalation and exhalation may decrease&lt;/strong&gt;. In this case it is recommended to first exaggerate both parts one after the other, i.e. more inhalation than exhalation and then more exhalation than inhalation. In this way you should directly feel the effects of the overemphasis of the respective breathing parts, so that your feeling for the right balance can increase. Pay attention to the sound of your breathing and let a steady rhythm develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You &lt;strong&gt;tense your face&lt;/strong&gt;. This is an indication that you are using your navel incorrectly. Your face should be soft and relaxed during the breath of fire, just as it is during the long deep breathing. Keep consciously feeling into your energy centers in your abdomen and upper body and perceive your face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❗ In general, it is important to &lt;strong&gt;start slowly&lt;/strong&gt; as a beginner in the practice of breath of fire and &lt;strong&gt;become familiar with the technique&lt;/strong&gt;. Approach slowly and increase the pace only when you have developed a feeling for the breath of fire. Over time, you will be able to feel the benefits of the breath of fire more directly and consciously. You can then enjoy these effects very intensely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish you a lot of joy in getting to know &amp;amp; practicing the breath of fire! 💫&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please also pay attention that this guide for breath of fire and your use of it is a decision you have to take on your own. I cannot promise to you that you&amp;rsquo;ll feel these benefits as well, as every human being is unique and therefore reacts individually. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure, if you can practice the breath of fire, please ask your doctor (as mentioned in my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/legal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;disclaimer&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/em&gt; ☝️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAT NAM!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The eighth chakra</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-eighth-chakra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-eighth-chakra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The journey through the eight chakras in Kundalini Yoga ends today with the last station: &lt;strong&gt;the aura&lt;/strong&gt;. Many chakra theories and also illustrations do not include the aura as the 8th chakra. In Kundalini Yoga, however, the aura has an equally important role as all other seven chakras that I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aura is located &lt;strong&gt;outside of your body&lt;/strong&gt;. It is related to your &lt;strong&gt;radiation&lt;/strong&gt;. The color of the aura is &lt;strong&gt;white&lt;/strong&gt; and is located in the &lt;strong&gt;electromagnetic field of your body&lt;/strong&gt;. It is not associated with any of the elements, but simply &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; with the &lt;strong&gt;feeling of being&lt;/strong&gt;. The aura gives you the space for yourself and fills it with yourself, with &lt;strong&gt;your presence&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the eighth chakra the effects of all other chakras are brought together. The aura also represents the power of the energy sphere that surrounds all other seven chakras, a kind of &lt;strong&gt;surrounding field&lt;/strong&gt;. Within the specific energy of the aura, the universal flow of energy becomes fixed. You can feel &lt;strong&gt;deep connectedness within you&lt;/strong&gt; through the power of your aura, as it interweaves you with the entire universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everyone has an aura&lt;/strong&gt;, some can even see the aura of others. You can also strengthen this ability within yourself.
Auras can be between three and nine feet in size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the element &lt;strong&gt;water&lt;/strong&gt; is good for your aura, for example when you go into the water, take a shower or a bath. This can &lt;strong&gt;change your aura&lt;/strong&gt;. Likewise, drinking water and letting water out of your body &lt;strong&gt;purifies&lt;/strong&gt; you and your aura and &lt;strong&gt;changes your emotions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your aura is your &lt;strong&gt;protective body&lt;/strong&gt; and also your &lt;strong&gt;projection body&lt;/strong&gt; that surrounds you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-strong-aura-&#34;&gt;A strong aura &amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… provides you with the ability to &lt;strong&gt;filter out negative influences&lt;/strong&gt; from your surroundings. Your other chakras can work better together. It creates a connection to the integrity of the electromagnetic field of your body. Your surrounding field will look &lt;strong&gt;round&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;symmetrical&lt;/strong&gt;, provided you are healthy. Then your presence alone will work for you. This means that &lt;strong&gt;universal forces will be directed to serve you&lt;/strong&gt;, to fulfill your wishes and needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-weak-aura-&#34;&gt;A weak aura &amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… on the other hand, makes you &lt;strong&gt;vulnerable to all external influences&lt;/strong&gt;. When you are sick, your aura has &lt;strong&gt;bulges&lt;/strong&gt; with weaker radiance and even &lt;strong&gt;holes&lt;/strong&gt;. It is then possible that you feel vulnerable, live a more withdrawn life and appear shy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kundalini-yoga--aura&#34;&gt;Kundalini Yoga &amp;amp; Aura&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also in connection with this chakra, your aura, you can use practices from the colorful world of &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt;.
To strengthen your aura, the following exercises from Kundalini Yoga can support you well if necessary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triangel Pose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ego Eradicator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archer Pose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All arm exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All meditations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, this list of exercises is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a panacea. Please &lt;strong&gt;always look for yourself individually, what exactly you can do in which way&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are uncertain, please always consult your doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a Kundalini Yoga class different chakras are usually touched and activated, often with a focus. If you would like to know more about this or if you would like to book a Kundalini Yoga session with me on a specific chakra or topic, please &lt;strong&gt;feel free to send me an email&lt;/strong&gt; as always. ✉️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date with my current posts, I invite you to follow me on my &lt;strong&gt;social media channels&lt;/strong&gt; (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;). 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The seventh chakra</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-seventh-chakra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-seventh-chakra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The journey through the eight chakras in Kundalini Yoga continues. Today the focus lies on the &lt;strong&gt;crown chakra&lt;/strong&gt; as a very important central chakra. It is located at the &lt;strong&gt;vertex of the head&lt;/strong&gt; and also above it and therefore slightly outside the body.
In Sanskrit this chakra is called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sahasrara&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be translated as &amp;ldquo;thousand times&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organically, the crown chakra is associated with the &lt;strong&gt;brain&lt;/strong&gt; and especially the &lt;strong&gt;pineal gland&lt;/strong&gt;. The chakra is represented with the color &lt;strong&gt;violet&lt;/strong&gt;. As an element in a broader sense, the &lt;strong&gt;cosmos&lt;/strong&gt; is associated here.
Thematically, the seventh chakra covers the areas of &lt;strong&gt;consciousness, fulfillment, spirituality and divine guidance&lt;/strong&gt;.  Through this chakra, a connection is created between humanity and divinity, to the greater whole, the &lt;strong&gt;cosmic consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;. Through this it is possible for us to gain &lt;strong&gt;access to the highest form of wisdom and knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; - through the process of fusion and unity. It is about understanding beyond the possibilities and limitations of the mind.
Important is also the &lt;strong&gt;activity and opening of the already known six other chakras&lt;/strong&gt;. The crown chakra cannot be consciously controlled in this sense - in contrast to the other six &amp;ldquo;underlying&amp;rdquo; chakras.
In addition, the &lt;strong&gt;kundalini energy&lt;/strong&gt;, which has already risen through the other chakras, comes together here. After this ascent, the kundalini energy moves back down to the root chakra.
Moreover, the &lt;strong&gt;hormonal balance&lt;/strong&gt; and the balance in the entire body system are also regulated here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important aspect of the crown chakra is &lt;strong&gt;humility&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;devotion&lt;/strong&gt;, which is shown by &lt;strong&gt;bowing to infinity&lt;/strong&gt;. Here you can also find an explanation for bowing: The vertex and thus seat of the seventh chakra is brought down to the earth when bowing. This creates a &lt;strong&gt;center of attention and direction of flow of the blood&lt;/strong&gt;. New feelings of openness and strength can be conveyed through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, when strengthening the crown chakra, care must be taken to &lt;strong&gt;avoid the development of a spiritual ego&lt;/strong&gt;. Here humility plays an important role in order not to gain the spiritual powers for the ego and for the sake of power. A connection to integrity and wholeness is accordingly important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-your-crown-chakra-is-open-&#34;&gt;When your crown chakra is open &amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; you experience the &lt;strong&gt;holistic transcendence of your identity as a separate person&lt;/strong&gt;. This step of development is often called &lt;strong&gt;enlightenment&lt;/strong&gt;. You feel a feeling of &lt;strong&gt;boundlessness&lt;/strong&gt;, without limitations. The world can be understood beyond your own mind. The intensive connection with the spiritual world enables a deep feeling of &lt;strong&gt;inner peace, completely connected with divine love&lt;/strong&gt;. Thus, fears on the inside become a strange, unrelated feeling.
The opening of the crown chakra also means an opening towards the &lt;strong&gt;divine guidance&lt;/strong&gt; in your own life. Everything that exists is perceived in unity and connectedness. Other people are met with &lt;strong&gt;compassion&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;tolerance&lt;/strong&gt;. There is no urge (anymore) to change the fellow human beings. Life contexts are understood deeper and deeper on the spiritual level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-your-sahasrara-also-be-blocked&#34;&gt;Can your Sahasrara also be blocked?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this chakra there exists more of an &lt;strong&gt;underdevelopment&lt;/strong&gt; than a mere blockage or disorder. This underdevelopment seems to be widespread.
If a lot of anger accumulates in someone and this anger is projected in a diffuse way to a higher force, this can lead to a &lt;strong&gt;total aversion and rejection of a connection to the Divine&lt;/strong&gt;.
On a psychological level, being cut off can lead to &lt;strong&gt;disorientation, spiritual emptiness&lt;/strong&gt; and finally &lt;strong&gt;uprooting&lt;/strong&gt;. Then the feeling of leading a meaningless life and ignorance of the true self can be present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Sahasrara.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sahasrara&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;main-characteristics-of-the-crown-chakra&#34;&gt;Main characteristics of the crown chakra&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit: Sahasrara&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Position: at and above the vertex of the head&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color: Purple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element: Cosmos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological function: Self-knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge: Attachment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I understand.&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;I have the right to know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kundalini-yoga--sahasrara&#34;&gt;Kundalini Yoga &amp;amp; Sahasrara&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of specific exercises from &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; can help you to open your crown chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ego Eradicator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mahaband&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sat Kriya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concentration on the tip of the nose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All meditations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, this list of exercises is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a panacea. Please &lt;strong&gt;always look for yourself individually, what exactly you can do in which way&lt;/strong&gt;! If you are uncertain, please always consult your doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a Kundalini Yoga session usually different chakras are touched and activated, often with a focus. If you would like to know more about this or if you would like to book a Kundalini Yoga session with me on a specific chakra or topic, please &lt;strong&gt;feel free to send me an email&lt;/strong&gt;. ✉️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my next blog post I will dedicate myself to the &lt;strong&gt;eighth&lt;/strong&gt; and thus last chakra of this series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep up to date with my current posts, I invite you to follow me on my &lt;strong&gt;social media channels&lt;/strong&gt; (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;). 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube &amp; me</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/youtube-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/youtube-and-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sat Nam, dear soul!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;news&lt;/strong&gt; at Ruha Healing and I am totally happy to share them with you. 🤗&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine, &lt;strong&gt;I have opened a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjR4h8QUBW_gUnXkfbEdKQA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Youtube Channel&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;
Wow, I would never have thought that myself. If someone had asked me a year ago if I would create Youtube videos, I rather would have said no. And today? The reality looks completely different than I thought - as so often. 😉 That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what makes it fun and exciting to live, that &lt;strong&gt;we never know what the future will bring and that we should always stay open and flexible for everything that comes&lt;/strong&gt;.
Now it actually happened that I am &lt;strong&gt;active on Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;. I do this mainly to serve you in the yogic sense. The channel should be a &lt;strong&gt;help for you to practice Kundalini Yoga regularly&lt;/strong&gt;, to dive deeper into this world and to connect with yourself through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-does-that-look-like-exactly&#34;&gt;How does that look like exactly?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on there will be &lt;strong&gt;regular uploads in my Youtube channel&lt;/strong&gt;. Once a month I would like to share a video from my &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga live sessions&lt;/strong&gt; with you. This gives you the opportunity to get a taste of the world of Kundalini Yoga and to gain practical experience. Of course you can also get to know me and my way of teaching.
I am very happy if you &lt;strong&gt;use this opportunity&lt;/strong&gt; and practice Kundalini Yoga with me. 🧘🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;curious&#34;&gt;Curious?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;strong&gt;have a look&lt;/strong&gt; directly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I share one of my Kundalini Yoga videos with you right now. Look at it with pleasure, spread out your mat and &lt;strong&gt;dive into the world of Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt;. I teach a &lt;strong&gt;Kriya for the nervous system&lt;/strong&gt; and end the class with the &lt;strong&gt;meditation for a calm heart&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✨&lt;em&gt;Wahe Guru!&lt;/em&gt; ✨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OIsdRLjWaMI&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-look-into-the-future&#34;&gt;A look into the future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I plan to upload smaller videos for you on Youtube &lt;strong&gt;regularly&lt;/strong&gt;. In these videos I would like to introduce you to many &lt;strong&gt;different aspects of Kundalini Yoga such as breathing techniques&lt;/strong&gt;. Your yoga practice can get a deep foundation, because in these videos I go even deeper into the material. This will be very &lt;strong&gt;enriching for your very individual practice&lt;/strong&gt;. I am already looking forward to creating and sharing my videos with y&amp;rsquo;all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-thats-not-all-&#34;&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not all &amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; because you can &lt;strong&gt;sign up for my ongoing Kundalini Yoga online sessions at any time&lt;/strong&gt;. It takes place &lt;strong&gt;every Sunday&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;first Wednesday of every month&lt;/strong&gt;. There we practice Kundalini Yoga online in a familiar circle on various topics of life. You are welcome to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/#next_sessions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;register&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;strong&gt;free trial session&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very happy to get to know you! 🥰&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date with my current posts, offers and more I invite you to follow me on my &lt;strong&gt;social media channels&lt;/strong&gt; (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;). 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is SADHANA?</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/what-is-sadhana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/what-is-sadhana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sadhana&lt;/strong&gt;. You may have heard about this specific term, which is especially used in the world of &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt;. But what’s that all about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article you will find a basic presentation of Sadhana as a core theme from Kundalini Yoga. You will learn what is done in Sadhana, what effects this can have, and how you can practice your own Sadhana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-sadhana&#34;&gt;What is Sadhana?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadhana means &lt;strong&gt;daily spiritual practice&lt;/strong&gt;. The aspect of “daily” is not to be neglected at all, since you will create an important &lt;strong&gt;foundation&lt;/strong&gt; through a very regular practice of &lt;strong&gt;spirituality&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requires a certain amount of &lt;strong&gt;self-discipline&lt;/strong&gt;, which in turn, gives you the opportunity to &lt;strong&gt;express infinity in your own self&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Kundalini Yoga, the practice of Sadhana has an important meaning, which is why it’s recommended to all yogis and yoginis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Sadhana, you open yourself up to the possibility to perceive and finally overcome any patterns that lead you away from your &lt;strong&gt;higher consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a &lt;strong&gt;consciously performed practice&lt;/strong&gt; that is meant to serve you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-are-the-6-steps-of-a-traditional-kundalini-sadhana&#34;&gt;Here are the 6 steps of a traditional Kundalini Sadhana:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classically, in the &lt;strong&gt;two and a half hours&lt;/strong&gt; before sunrise, you practice the following things in this specific order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recitation&lt;/strong&gt;
The Japji Sahib is a prayer from Sikhism, which is recited and chanted in a meditative way at the start of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chanting&lt;/strong&gt;
The “Ong Namo Guru Dev Namo” mantra is used to begin all Kundalini practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kriya&lt;/strong&gt;
Next, you practice a Kriya of Kundalini Yoga to keep your physical body fit, strengthen circulation, release tension, and stimulate the Kundalini energy within you. A Kriya consists of movements, breathwork, chanting, and meditation.
The choice of the Kriya is not prescribed, although certain Kriyas are particularly suitable for Sadhana. Those that work on the respiration, glands, nerves, and spine in a balanced way are especially useful. The Kriya should be generally energizing.
As usual, the Kriya ends with deep relaxation and is followed by meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;
&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read the &lt;strong&gt;full article&lt;/strong&gt; on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yogiapproved.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;YogiApproved&lt;/a&gt;, click &lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yogiapproved.com/om/kundalini-sadhana/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sixth chakra</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-sixth-chakra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-sixth-chakra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having already got to know the fifth chakra as the beginning of the upper triangle, you can now explore the sixth chakra, the brow chakra. In Sanskrit the brow chakra is known as &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ajna&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, which translated means &amp;ldquo;to command&amp;rdquo;. Therefore the sixth chakra is also called the &lt;strong&gt;command chakra&lt;/strong&gt;. Even better known is the name &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;third eye&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a very common term for many yogis &amp;amp; yoginis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brow chakra is located, as can be assumed, in the area of the forehead &lt;strong&gt;between and slightly above the eyebrows&lt;/strong&gt;. Organically, the &lt;strong&gt;brain&lt;/strong&gt; and especially the &lt;strong&gt;pituitary gland (hypophysis)&lt;/strong&gt; are assigned to this chakra.
In the spectrum of colors we are now in the range of &lt;strong&gt;indigo&lt;/strong&gt; (dark purple). In addition, this chakra is often represented by &lt;strong&gt;light&lt;/strong&gt; - as an assigned characteristic. Here the &lt;strong&gt;inner light&lt;/strong&gt; is meant.
The elements (earth, water, fire, air, ether) are left with the third eye, which means we are now &lt;strong&gt;moving outside the five elements&lt;/strong&gt; that can be related to the previous chakras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main focus of the third eye is on &lt;strong&gt;intuition&lt;/strong&gt;, but also &lt;strong&gt;wisdom&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;identity&lt;/strong&gt;. Through the brow chakra you can gain &lt;strong&gt;integrity&lt;/strong&gt; and intuition and get a feeling for them, and finally go your very own way, to &lt;strong&gt;take the direction of your soul&lt;/strong&gt;. Your soul can thus be guided by your intuition. The brow chakra is also called the &lt;strong&gt;gateway to the soul&lt;/strong&gt; and thus to higher spiritual experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your third eye is also for &lt;strong&gt;setting goals&lt;/strong&gt; and anticipating the &lt;strong&gt;long-term effects of your actions&lt;/strong&gt;. This chakra is therefore also characterized by &lt;strong&gt;cultivation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;projection&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two physical eyes allow us to see into the &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; world, but the third eye goes beyond that. It gives us *&lt;strong&gt;depth, vision and scope into the subtle worlds&lt;/strong&gt;. The sense and perception itself is expanded far beyond physical reality. An &lt;strong&gt;opening to divine consciousness and the higher dimensions&lt;/strong&gt; is then possible. Herein lies the origin of knowledge and the experience of being more than just your own body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brow chakra is represented by two petals, as you can see in the picture. These symbolise the &lt;strong&gt;duality of mind that needs to be overcome&lt;/strong&gt;. Duality is that every thought consists of a plus and a minus. When you master the sixth chakra, the opposites of life will no longer confuse you. You will be equipped with the &lt;strong&gt;ability to read between the polarities or lines&lt;/strong&gt;. Interestingly, the associated gland, the pituitary gland, also consists of two parts: anterior and posterior pituitary. Thus, an existing duality is even visible in our body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;unification of opposites&lt;/strong&gt; is also addressed here. Thus, the three main energy channels Ida, Pingala and Sushmana flow together here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-your-third-eye-is-open&#34;&gt;When your third eye is open&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;then &lt;strong&gt;deep spiritual realms of experience&lt;/strong&gt; will be revealed to you. You are characterized by &lt;strong&gt;clairvoyance, imagination&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;good visualization&lt;/strong&gt;. You can perceive ideas as inner pictures and &lt;strong&gt;let your own intuition lead you&lt;/strong&gt;. Here in the third eye is the centre of your intuition, with which you get in touch. This is accompanied by a good imagination.
You will also be focused and determined and move through your life in a &lt;strong&gt;self-initiated&lt;/strong&gt; way.
You will &lt;strong&gt;understand the meaning and content of your life&lt;/strong&gt; with an open brow chakra, i.e. with access to your intuition and wisdom. You can &lt;strong&gt;attain awareness of the Divine within yourself&lt;/strong&gt; and in everything that surrounds you and us. Deep spiritual experiences of cosmic consciousness are made possible for you. Likewise, a &lt;strong&gt;close communication with your soul&lt;/strong&gt; is established and you become noticeably more sensitive to your intuition the more your Ajna is opened. For some people even &lt;strong&gt;telepathic communication&lt;/strong&gt; is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ajna-in-imbalance&#34;&gt;Ajna in imbalance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a disturbed brow chakra, states of &lt;strong&gt;confusion&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;depression&lt;/strong&gt; are possible. The own thoughts then often revolve around &lt;strong&gt;fears&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;worries&lt;/strong&gt;, which leads to a kind of &lt;strong&gt;mental forlornness&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;lack of orientation&lt;/strong&gt;. As a result, feelings of &lt;strong&gt;senselessness&lt;/strong&gt; arise, which have a corresponding effect on the state of mind.
In addition, &lt;strong&gt;lack of concentration, illusionary realities, nightmares, delusions&lt;/strong&gt; and even &lt;strong&gt;hallucinations&lt;/strong&gt; can occur. The brow chakra is then active, but in a disturbed way.
Furthermore, spirituality is often &lt;strong&gt;rejected&lt;/strong&gt; by people with a blocked Ajna. This is because everything is much more viewed from the &lt;strong&gt;material and mind-controlled, intellectual level&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, only that which is visible, measurable or has an analytical background has value. This then leads to an &lt;strong&gt;excess of intellectualization&lt;/strong&gt; because the intellectual mind is overemphasized. There is the eternal attempt to have to understand everything rationally. Things and events are always questioned mentally. The reason for this can partly be the educated world view and belief system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Ajna.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ajna&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;main-characteristics-of-the-third-eye&#34;&gt;Main characteristics of the Third Eye&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit: Ajna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Position: Forehead, between the eyebrows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color: Indigo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element: Light&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological function: Self-reflection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge: Illusions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archetypal identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I see.&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;I have the right to see.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kundalini-yoga--ajna&#34;&gt;Kundalini Yoga &amp;amp; Ajna&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of specific exercises from &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; can help you to open or rebalance your brow chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditations on the third eye&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long chanting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kirtan Kriya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archer Pose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whistling Breathing Exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoga mudra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All exercises with the forehead on the floor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially the &lt;strong&gt;chanting of &amp;ldquo;Ong&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; stimulates the cave in the cranium where the pituitary gland is located.
The vibration of the cave &lt;strong&gt;awakens the pituitary gland&lt;/strong&gt; and thus triggers a more active relationship with the other higher gland, the &lt;strong&gt;pineal gland&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this list of exercises is not a panacea. &lt;strong&gt;Please always look for yourself individually, what exactly you can do in which way.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are uncertain, please always consult your doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a Kundalini Yoga session usually different chakras are touched and activated, often with a focus. If you would like to know more about this or if you would like to book a Kundalini Yoga session with me on a specific chakra or topic, please &lt;strong&gt;feel free to send me an email&lt;/strong&gt; as usual. ✉️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my next blog post I will dedicate myself to the &lt;strong&gt;seventh chakra&lt;/strong&gt;. To keep up to date with my current posts, I invite you to follow me on my &lt;strong&gt;social media channels&lt;/strong&gt; (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;). 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fifth chakra</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-fifth-chakra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-fifth-chakra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the fifth chakra, after the lower triangle, the second triangle begins, which can be found among the chakras: the &lt;strong&gt;upper triangle&lt;/strong&gt;. This fifth chakra, known as the throat chakra, is called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Vissudha&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; in Sanskrit. Translated this means &lt;strong&gt;purity&lt;/strong&gt;. The upper and lower triangle are connected by Anahata, the heart chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The throat chakra, as the name suggests, is located in the &lt;strong&gt;throat centre&lt;/strong&gt;. On an organic level, the &lt;strong&gt;thyroid and parathyroid glands, trachea, throat and neck vertebrae&lt;/strong&gt; are connected to this chakra.
The colour for this chakra is &lt;strong&gt;light blue&lt;/strong&gt;. On a sensual level this is the level of &lt;strong&gt;hearing&lt;/strong&gt;. 👂🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central theme of the throat chakra is the &lt;strong&gt;projected power of the word&lt;/strong&gt;, which means hearing and speaking the truth. It is also about the &lt;strong&gt;expression of the soul&lt;/strong&gt; and expressiveness in general, but also about &lt;strong&gt;authenticity, truth and higher self&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, experiences of your self-expression are processed, whereby it is mainly about the &lt;strong&gt;highest expression of your soul&lt;/strong&gt;. A connection with the higher mind can be established if your throat chakra is permeable. Herein lies the source of &lt;strong&gt;understanding&lt;/strong&gt; and the ability to &lt;strong&gt;communicate&lt;/strong&gt;. Your very own search for truth lies hidden in this chakra and can be carried outwards through your communication as well as through contacts and wishes.
With the help of this specific energy from the throat chakra you can achieve &lt;strong&gt;self-determination, freedom&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;independence&lt;/strong&gt;. You can re-evaluate any beliefs you have learned through your own truth filter and thus live out these values. Consequently, there is room for the &lt;strong&gt;expression of your soul&amp;rsquo;s individuality&lt;/strong&gt; - through &lt;strong&gt;communication&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;creative self-expression&lt;/strong&gt; like for example dance or art. 💃🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;connection with your higher self&lt;/strong&gt; is made possible through the throat chakra. Through this, soul messages as well as your own destiny can be felt free of any conditions. The identification with your own ego can be transcended through this chakra so that you can &lt;strong&gt;live your true self&lt;/strong&gt;. An &lt;strong&gt;opening to the higher levels of the subtle dimension&lt;/strong&gt; is also made possible. Now the greater connection behind all things can be recognized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;just-say-it&#34;&gt;Just say it!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive deeper into the realm of &lt;strong&gt;communication&lt;/strong&gt;, of language. Everything starts with your &lt;strong&gt;spoken word&lt;/strong&gt; (Vaak Siddhi), which is the highest of all seeds (Bija). This is the power that initiates manifestations of physical forms or actions solely through the utterance of the words. These are then the &lt;strong&gt;seeds for the emerging manifestations&lt;/strong&gt;. Transmitted this means that the power of man is so strong when it comes to determining the direction of an action. The seeds are planted and from that moment on they are handed over to the laws of Maya. From then on it is difficult to change the course of events, because &lt;strong&gt;things have already been set in motion&lt;/strong&gt;, the seed has already spread its roots and &lt;strong&gt;growth&lt;/strong&gt; is taking place. 🌱&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;spoken word&lt;/strong&gt; stands for &lt;strong&gt;power to plant the seeds&lt;/strong&gt;, which in turn can fulfill the highest &lt;strong&gt;destiny&lt;/strong&gt; of someone. So if the word is mastered and with it the ability to initiate the actions that come out of the soul, then the gate to the higher regions of this upper triangle can be opened. This is why the throat chakra is also called an &lt;strong&gt;enormous gate&lt;/strong&gt;.
The power of &lt;strong&gt;projection&lt;/strong&gt; is also not to be despised here.
Communication in general is rather blunt, according to the motto &amp;ldquo;So be it&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-the-throat-chakra-is-open-&#34;&gt;When the throat chakra is open &amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; then you experience the perception of the &lt;strong&gt;subtle&lt;/strong&gt; and are able to &lt;strong&gt;express yourself and your own truth&lt;/strong&gt;. You can express sensations, feelings and attitudes freely and openly and have a preference for communication itself. This also means that disputes are not problems in themselves, as they are usually considered to broaden horizons. &lt;strong&gt;Speaking clearly&lt;/strong&gt; and getting things to the point is generally not difficult. But it is also &lt;strong&gt;easy to listen&lt;/strong&gt;, and this also means being able to &lt;strong&gt;understand other people - as well as yourself - from a higher perspective&lt;/strong&gt;. At the same time, the own weaknesses are also accepted.
People with an open throat chakra can &lt;strong&gt;improvise&lt;/strong&gt; well. Furthermore, openness towards different kinds of &lt;strong&gt;inspiration&lt;/strong&gt; prevails.
The own wishes and the ability to manifest and fulfil them in the own life are perceived.
Basically, the &lt;strong&gt;expression of the own intuition or soul is undisturbed&lt;/strong&gt;. You can let yourself be led trustingly by your &lt;strong&gt;inner guidance&lt;/strong&gt;, your intuition. With this you are &lt;strong&gt;authentic&lt;/strong&gt; to yourself as well as to others and are in a more integral connection to your soul. It comes to an &lt;strong&gt;end of the identification with the ego&lt;/strong&gt;, which enables the opening for the pure expression of the soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;out-of-balance&#34;&gt;Out of balance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If, on the other hand, the throat chakra is disturbed, this can be due to &lt;strong&gt;painful experiences&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;lack of self-expression&lt;/strong&gt; as the being you are. Especially difficult life situations at the &lt;strong&gt;age of 16 to 21 years&lt;/strong&gt; can have a negative effect on the development of the throat chakra and inhibit developments. The consequences are, for example, a &lt;strong&gt;disturbed self-expression&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;disturbed communication with the environment&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition, &lt;strong&gt;needs, wishes etc. cannot be communicated&lt;/strong&gt; and others cannot be listened to. The &lt;strong&gt;inner fear of contact with others&lt;/strong&gt; can then lead to &lt;strong&gt;inhibitions&lt;/strong&gt;, which can also be explained by fear of rejection, criticism, loss of control and negative reactions in general. These fears, in turn, can lead to constructs of &lt;strong&gt;lies, exaggerations&lt;/strong&gt; and even &lt;strong&gt;bizarre self-dramatization&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition to uptightness, apathy can also occur in some cases. This whole behaviour serves as a &lt;strong&gt;protection&lt;/strong&gt;, because nobody else is shown with the true self. To the outside world these people do not show themselves clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, there is often &lt;strong&gt;no access to the inner self&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;no trust in the own intuition&lt;/strong&gt;. The self-confidence is low or even non-existent. In extreme cases, speech disorders occur.
The world is also often perceived as &lt;strong&gt;colourless&lt;/strong&gt; and poor, as the ability to dream, try out and improvise is rather poor.
All this leaves &lt;strong&gt;pain&lt;/strong&gt; for the own soul and can lead to &lt;strong&gt;remorse, self-condemnation&lt;/strong&gt; and an &lt;strong&gt;excessive hardness&lt;/strong&gt; towards oneself.
On the physical level, possible symptoms include recurring inflammation of the throat and mouth or hyper- or hypothyroidism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;element-ether&#34;&gt;Element Ether&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The throat chakra is dominated by the &lt;strong&gt;etheric element&lt;/strong&gt;, which provides insights into the wondrous and mystical. Ether is considered the &lt;strong&gt;most subtle of all elements&lt;/strong&gt; (besides earth, water, fire and air). Ether is regarded to be a &lt;strong&gt;state of time and space&lt;/strong&gt; that allows a thing to exist. Thus this element is the very beginning of the &lt;strong&gt;manifestation process&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Vishuddha.png&#34; alt=&#34;Vissudha&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;main-features-of-the-heart-chakra&#34;&gt;Main features of the heart chakra&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit: Vissudha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Position: Throat, neck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color: light blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element: Ether&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological function: Self-expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge: Lying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creative identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I talk.&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;I have the right to speak and be heard.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kundalini-yoga--vissudha&#34;&gt;Kundalini Yoga &amp;amp; Vissudha&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To activate this chakra or to bring it back into balance, the following yoga exercises from &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; can help you. 🧘🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any chanting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shoulder stand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cobra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plow pose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camel position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cat - Cow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neck rolls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neck Lock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nose to the knees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, these exercises are not a panacea and you have to &lt;strong&gt;look for yourself individually, what exactly you can do in which way&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are uncertain, please always consult your doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga session&lt;/strong&gt; usually different chakras are touched and activated, often with a focus. If you would like to know more about this or if you would like to book a Kundalini Yoga session with me on a specific chakra or topic, please &lt;strong&gt;feel free to send me an email&lt;/strong&gt; as usual. ✉️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my next blog post I will focus on the &lt;strong&gt;sixth chakra&lt;/strong&gt;. To keep up to date with my current posts, I invite you to follow me on my social media channels (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;). 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fourth chakra</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-fourth-chakra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-fourth-chakra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having already got to know the first three chakras as the lower triangle, you will get some insights into the fourth chakra, the heart chakra, today. In Sanskrit it is called &lt;strong&gt;Anahata&lt;/strong&gt; and can be translated as &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;not beaten sound&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. It is a sound that is not produced externally, i.e. without the clash of two things. This alone brings a certain fascination and enables us to look beyond the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heart chakra, as the name suggests, is located in the &lt;strong&gt;heart space in the middle of the chest on the sternum&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;heart&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;lungs&lt;/strong&gt; are assigned to this chakra as organs, as well as the &lt;strong&gt;thymus gland&lt;/strong&gt;.
As far as the colors are concerned, we are now in the space of &lt;strong&gt;pink&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;green&lt;/strong&gt;, where pink means the heart itself and green emphasizes more the protection of the heart. As a rule, however, only the color green is referred to. 💚&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heart chakra is located &lt;strong&gt;exactly in the middle of the first seven chakras&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;connects the lower triangle&lt;/strong&gt; (first 3 chakras) &lt;strong&gt;to the upper triangle&lt;/strong&gt; ( 5th to 7th chakra). Thus it connects the &lt;strong&gt;worldly dimension&lt;/strong&gt; (lower triangle), our &lt;strong&gt;humanity&lt;/strong&gt;, with the &lt;strong&gt;spiritual level&lt;/strong&gt; (upper triangle), our &lt;strong&gt;soul&lt;/strong&gt;. It provides a balance between the lower energy flow of the earth and the flow of the upper energies of heaven and prepares the way &lt;strong&gt;from the I to the WE&lt;/strong&gt;.
The heart chakra, as the first chakra, becomes completely subtle.
The main focus within this chakra is on &lt;strong&gt;love, awakening, trust, devotion, pain and forgiveness&lt;/strong&gt;. 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;love-love-love&#34;&gt;Love, love, love&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Anahata has enormous power and significance. It processes the experiences of love as well as the subtle feelings and sensations associated with love. The energy of the heart chakra develops your capacity for &lt;strong&gt;unconditional love and devotion&lt;/strong&gt;. In the heart dwells the &lt;strong&gt;pure, universal love of your soul&lt;/strong&gt;. This brings with it the ability to accept all people and events with a &lt;strong&gt;non-judgmental&lt;/strong&gt; acceptance, i.e. with &lt;strong&gt;neutrality&lt;/strong&gt;. Through the love that then permeates you, you can feel and learn your own inner truth without condemnation. A space is opened to you in which you can feel everything. No pain or darkness can damage this strong unconditional love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the complex world of human love opens up and relationships of real love become possible. This is where you are prepared for deeper love, the &lt;strong&gt;spiritual love of the soul&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;cosmic love&lt;/strong&gt;. The search for love in the outside then ideally leads to &lt;strong&gt;finding love within yourself as a source&lt;/strong&gt;. By embodying love, because it is within you, you also give it to the outside, so that your &lt;strong&gt;light of love&lt;/strong&gt; can be reflected and fulfilled in the world. With this experience you can let yourself fall even more into yourself, open yourself to the inside, because you do not (any longer) need the outside for feeling love. You can always get in contact with love, because it always flows.
This love finally also enables you to &lt;strong&gt;forgive from the heart&lt;/strong&gt;. ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another characteristic is the &lt;strong&gt;sensitivity&lt;/strong&gt; that this chakra brings with it. Here you are touchable up to your soul and you can also feel other people with their true self. In addition, a &lt;strong&gt;universal consciousness of connectedness&lt;/strong&gt; can arise in you, which goes beyond the realm of your personality.
Your heart centre determines the subtle feeling and the ability to touch. When a person speaks from his/her heart, this touches us, as it penetrates to our innermost being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central is also the topic of &lt;strong&gt;healing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;spiritual growth&lt;/strong&gt;. Through the contact to your own soul you come closer to yourself and can stimulate a healing process. Personality and ego are then transcended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Kundalini Yoga by Yogi Bhajan the mind is divided into three different minds: negative, positive and neutral. What exactly this means, I will explain to you in a separate blog post. The heart chakra definitely also refers to the area of the &lt;strong&gt;neutral mind&lt;/strong&gt;, as this is necessary to give other people the same &lt;strong&gt;value&lt;/strong&gt; we would attribute to ourselves.
Here in the fourth chakra there is a &lt;strong&gt;conflict-free state&lt;/strong&gt; in which heaven and earth come together in balance. Inside and outside merge in a perception of &lt;strong&gt;flowing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The already mentioned lower three chakras embody, among other things, the cultivation as well as mastery of the impulse, whereby the feeling of the &lt;strong&gt;ego&lt;/strong&gt; is present. When your heart chakra opens, you reach the first &lt;strong&gt;true level of self-reflective consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;. You can see yourself through the eyes of others and realize that other beings are as important as yourself. Thus the feeling of &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; shifts more to a feeling of &lt;strong&gt;WE&lt;/strong&gt;. An important basis for this is a &lt;strong&gt;powerful, stable self&lt;/strong&gt; (through a strong lower triangle) to open your heart chakra. If your lower triangle is still too weak or even disturbed, then the love of your heart can be pulled again and again into the dynamic of the needs of the lower three chakras and in the end be distorted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your heart chakra is open there is a &lt;strong&gt;connection between your heart and your mind in the light of your soul&lt;/strong&gt;. Your soul can then express itself in your personality. This is also called the &lt;strong&gt;gateway to other dimensions of being&lt;/strong&gt;. People with an open heart chakra have recognized the source of love and love themselves &lt;strong&gt;unconditionally&lt;/strong&gt;. In life they let themselves be guided by their sensations of the heart, which is also called &lt;strong&gt;heart intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;.
There is a &lt;strong&gt;devotional and expectation-free love&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;acceptance&lt;/strong&gt; towards all living beings present, because a &lt;strong&gt;feeling for the soul&lt;/strong&gt; is felt deep inside the others. Through this &lt;strong&gt;universal love&lt;/strong&gt; from within, there is a radiance to the outside, which is also perceptible for the environment. 💓&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;True &lt;strong&gt;joy&lt;/strong&gt; of the heart and much &lt;strong&gt;laughter&lt;/strong&gt; are present, as well as &lt;strong&gt;warmth, love, compassion, sensitivity, gentleness&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;patience&lt;/strong&gt; are felt within oneself. A deep feeling of &lt;strong&gt;gratitude&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;connectedness&lt;/strong&gt; with all that is is created.
The relationship to the own feelings is renewed and they can be consciously recognized and controlled. Furthermore, people with an open Anahata give themselves as well as all others the &lt;strong&gt;freedom to grow independently&lt;/strong&gt; and to accept any path in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the heart chakra can also be described as another &lt;strong&gt;immune system&lt;/strong&gt; that knows when something is a foreign or belonging part. This means that you know how to include people appropriately in each of your relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s also look at the area of &lt;strong&gt;communication&lt;/strong&gt;: communication from the heart center includes others as well as yourself. You speak with &lt;strong&gt;empathy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;kindness&lt;/strong&gt; to yourself and others. You are aware of the person to whom your communication is directed. Thus a feeling of &lt;strong&gt;presence&lt;/strong&gt; can be perceived by all participants. The language here is &lt;strong&gt;true&lt;/strong&gt;, but always &lt;strong&gt;friendly&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-the-heart-chakra-also-be-disturbed&#34;&gt;Can the heart chakra also be disturbed?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your heart chakra can also show blockages or disorders that can have various causes - like every other chakra. In general the &lt;strong&gt;experience and feeling of being separated from love&lt;/strong&gt; can lead to a traumatic experience. &lt;strong&gt;Strong emotional pain&lt;/strong&gt; can then trigger blockages in the Anahata. This in turn can lead to &lt;strong&gt;distrust&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;refusal&lt;/strong&gt; or even &lt;strong&gt;inability to love or be loved&lt;/strong&gt;. Blockages can also be caused by feelings of resentment or revenge, which in turn have their own individual history. The connection to the own heart can also be interrupted if a person has done something to others, which can lead to a strain on the soul and finally to &lt;strong&gt;self rejection or condemnation&lt;/strong&gt;. 💔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, one of the two poles of relationship is usually &lt;strong&gt;overemphasized&lt;/strong&gt;: a narcissistic self-centredness and refusal to face the world or a self-sacrificing dependence on the love of others, even to the point of self-abandonment or even self-hate. Thus, overactivity of the heart chakra may lead to an &lt;strong&gt;excess of compassion&lt;/strong&gt;. An undersupply, in turn, can end in &lt;strong&gt;dependence&lt;/strong&gt; and a disturbed feeling for the own self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-element-air&#34;&gt;The element air&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The element assigned to the Anahata is &lt;strong&gt;air&lt;/strong&gt;. It is symbolized by the &lt;strong&gt;breath&lt;/strong&gt;, which creates a &lt;strong&gt;connecting flow between you and creation&lt;/strong&gt; - by the fact that the air surrounding you enters you and exits again as the breath of life, touching the world. Allow what is also hidden behind your breath to work on you&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-i-touch-that&#34;&gt;Can I touch that?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you can also find one of our senses, which is assigned to this chakra: the &lt;strong&gt;sense of touch&lt;/strong&gt;. This means above all to &lt;strong&gt;feel, perceive, touch and be touched&lt;/strong&gt; on various levels.
Also the connection to the &lt;strong&gt;hands&lt;/strong&gt; stands for the ability to touch and feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Anahata.png&#34; alt=&#34;Anahata&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;main-features-of-the-heart-chakra&#34;&gt;Main features of the heart chakra&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit: Anahata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Position: Heart centre, in the middle of the chest on the sternum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color: Green (and Pink)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element: Air&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological function: self-acceptance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge: Grief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I love.&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;I have the right to love and be loved.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kundalini-yoga--anahata&#34;&gt;Kundalini Yoga &amp;amp; Anahata&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would we do without Kundalini Yoga, that&amp;rsquo;s what I sometimes think. It is such a powerful resource for us human beings here on earth that I am enthusiastic about this style of yoga and its possibilities every time. You can also find specific exercises that work on your heart chakra and can release blockages and connect to other chakras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ego Eradicator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoga Mudra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bear grip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baby Pose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All arm exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercises that rotate the upper part of the upper body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Pranayama exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the &lt;strong&gt;sound&lt;/strong&gt; is also explicitly mentioned here. The sound &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ham&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; can open your heart chakra and activate the relationship with the fifth chakra. The Anahata is stimulated by Prana, so that the use of &lt;strong&gt;Pranayama&lt;/strong&gt; (breathing techniques) stimulates your heart space in a powerful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, please look for yourself to see what works and what does not, where your &lt;strong&gt;individual possibilities and limits&lt;/strong&gt; lie! This small list can serve as an aid, which you are welcome to try out if you feel like working on your fourth chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga session&lt;/strong&gt; usually different chakras are touched and activated, often with a focus. If you would like to know more about this or if you would like to book a Kundalini Yoga session with me on a specific chakra or topic, please &lt;strong&gt;feel free to send me an email&lt;/strong&gt; as always. ✉️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my next blog post I will focus on the &lt;strong&gt;fifth chakra&lt;/strong&gt;. To keep up to date with my current posts, I invite you to follow me on my social media channels (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;). 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The third chakra</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-third-chakra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-third-chakra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-journey-of-the-chakras-continues-&#34;&gt;The journey of the chakras continues &amp;hellip;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; with the third chakra, also known as the &lt;strong&gt;navel or solar plexus chakra&lt;/strong&gt;. The Sanskrit name for this chakra is &lt;strong&gt;Manipura&lt;/strong&gt;. Manipura translates as &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;city of jewels.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third chakra can be located in the area of the &lt;strong&gt;navel point to just above the solar plexus&lt;/strong&gt;, also known as the &amp;ldquo;sun network&amp;rdquo;. On a physical level several organs are assigned to this chakra: &lt;strong&gt;liver, gall bladder, spleen, digestive organs, pancreas, adrenal glands and solar plexus&lt;/strong&gt;.
In terms of color, we are now at the color &lt;strong&gt;yellow&lt;/strong&gt;. Together with the first and second chakra, the &lt;strong&gt;lower triangle&lt;/strong&gt; is completed by the navel chakra.
Central issues within this chakra are &lt;strong&gt;action&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;balance, thought patterns and beliefs, personality, power, willpower and control&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, the third chakra is the &lt;strong&gt;center of energy and willpower&lt;/strong&gt;, which comes together with a sense of &lt;strong&gt;coordination and control&lt;/strong&gt;. The basic energetic balance is massively influenced by the third chakra. The mentioned topics are linked to the &lt;strong&gt;self-conception&lt;/strong&gt; you have as a human being and your personal power and strength. This is your &lt;strong&gt;driving force&lt;/strong&gt;, which ultimately brings you into action - also to realize your own ideas.
Ideally, the topic of power expresses itself through &lt;strong&gt;self-confidence, integrity&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;ability to act&lt;/strong&gt;. 💪🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A central concept here is also &lt;strong&gt;personality&lt;/strong&gt;. Within this chakra your experiences and complex emotions are digested and translated into a mental structure. This is also where the relationship to the digestive organs becomes visible. Your own mental concepts emerge, which in turn are fundamental for the processing of conscious and unconscious experiences. A &lt;strong&gt;mental structure of thoughts and beliefs&lt;/strong&gt; is formed, which then develops into the self-perception of your own personality. Thus, in addition to all life experiences, your own &lt;strong&gt;identity&lt;/strong&gt; or a collection of different identities is formed. Through the solar plexus chakra you can get access to these identities - in the form of fears and deep-seated unconscious thought and behavior patterns.
Furthermore, &lt;strong&gt;your own personality is THE possibility to let the light of your soul radiate into the world&lt;/strong&gt;. ✨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third chakra is also identified as the &lt;strong&gt;gateway to the fourth chakra&lt;/strong&gt;, where the space of the unconscious is left. This &lt;strong&gt;unconscious&lt;/strong&gt; is concentrated in the entire lower triangle. The heart centre in the fourth chakra marks the starting point for the &lt;strong&gt;consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;. In the solar plexus chakra the &lt;strong&gt;subconscious&lt;/strong&gt; as well as the &lt;strong&gt;gut feeling&lt;/strong&gt; is processed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;navel-center--its-power&#34;&gt;Navel center &amp;amp; it&amp;rsquo;s power&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the &lt;strong&gt;navel centre&lt;/strong&gt;, which can also be seen as a symbol for the &lt;strong&gt;beginning&lt;/strong&gt;. The navel point is the first point through which a person is nourished, i.e. supplied with energy. After birth, this navel point, which still exists, serves to &lt;strong&gt;absorb cosmic energy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also interesting to note the positive effect that the alternate movement of arms and legs has on our system, such as when we &lt;strong&gt;go for a walk&lt;/strong&gt;. This is because &lt;strong&gt;energy is accumulated at the navel point&lt;/strong&gt;, which is accordingly available to us. The third chakra therefore also houses the &lt;strong&gt;energy reserve of the body&lt;/strong&gt;.
In addition, from the navel point the &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini energy&lt;/strong&gt; is set in motion and sent on its journey upwards. With this power we can penetrate into the &lt;strong&gt;higher levels of consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;, which lie above the navel chakra.
On this basis it also makes sense that it is important to stimulate, strengthen and finally distribute the energy at the navel point. This can be done, for example, through the Kundalini Yoga Asana &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stretching Pose&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be performed for a few minutes directly in the morning to stimulate the energy.
It is also related to the feeling for the presence of sufficient energy to support your own actions. This energy can then be projected with willpower to encourage action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;totally-in-balance-&#34;&gt;Totally in balance 💛&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This third chakra also represents the need and the drive to &lt;strong&gt;realize your own ideas and wishes, to master challenges and to test yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. It gives you &lt;strong&gt;strength for change, discipline and self-transformation&lt;/strong&gt; - besides the need for &lt;strong&gt;control&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have mastered the third chakra, you have gained the knowledge of how to initiate and end an action. You are able to recognize your own &lt;strong&gt;mission&lt;/strong&gt; and create enough energy to act so that this mission can be accomplished. Furthermore, you are connected to your higher consciousness and use your &lt;strong&gt;fearlessness&lt;/strong&gt; to act with &lt;strong&gt;integrity&lt;/strong&gt;, regardless of the conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a well-functioning, open navel chakra, your own life as well as the quality of life is dependent on your own &lt;strong&gt;actions&lt;/strong&gt;. Often you can find so-called &amp;ldquo;doers&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;action people&amp;rdquo; who are seldom calm, because they do a lot and are in action. Even weak intentions generate actions. The actions from this chakra are focused and characterized by &lt;strong&gt;tactical intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;. Thus, &lt;strong&gt;goals can be achieved despite possible obstacles&lt;/strong&gt; and emerging challenges do not become a barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the ability to direct, shape and develop what happens in life, which ultimately leads to &lt;strong&gt;deep trust&lt;/strong&gt; and a feeling of &lt;strong&gt;security&lt;/strong&gt;. This can also explain why these people are often perceived by others as being at peace with themselves and having strong nerves. A dominance in the third chakra also ensures &lt;strong&gt;exuberance&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;expression&lt;/strong&gt;. There is a relationship to your own feelings, which are also used to achieve your goals. The own feelings can be reflected in an enriching way and stressful situations can be approached in a concentrated and peaceful way.
In addition, the ideas about your own abilities are very &lt;strong&gt;realistic&lt;/strong&gt; and also your opinion is lived out in a healthy way. People take &lt;strong&gt;responsibility&lt;/strong&gt; and cannot be manipulated. They have found their place in life and are about to &lt;strong&gt;fulfil their mission&lt;/strong&gt;. They also possess a high degree of integrity and &lt;strong&gt;decision-making ability&lt;/strong&gt; and can set themselves apart from the environment in a healthy way. Their own strengths and weaknesses are known by themselves. Their &lt;strong&gt;self-esteem&lt;/strong&gt; is healthy and they have the ability for &lt;strong&gt;self-reflection&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;discipline&lt;/strong&gt;.
Basically you can meet here &lt;strong&gt;adult, mature personalities&lt;/strong&gt; who have integrated their &amp;ldquo;inner child&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;not-enough-energy&#34;&gt;Not enough energy&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is too little energy in the navel chakra or if it is disturbed, this can have various effects on the individual life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feeling of lack of energy leads to a recourse to &lt;strong&gt;other energy sources&lt;/strong&gt; (for example through drugs or food), through which new energy can be accumulated. It should be obvious that this kind of energy supply is rather of an unhealthy nature. An urge to &lt;strong&gt;compensate&lt;/strong&gt; is also being exerted through this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, although there are good ideas and intentions, they are not put into practice. This is due to &lt;strong&gt;the lack of energy, which prevents the action from taking place&lt;/strong&gt;.
Also the emotional-mental processing of experiences can be blocked, which leads to an &lt;strong&gt;overwhelming of experiences and feelings&lt;/strong&gt;. This in turn leads to a suppression of emotional expressions with the attempt of &lt;strong&gt;control&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;rationalisation&lt;/strong&gt;.
Often an undersupply or disturbance of this chakra also leads to being overwhelmed by the challenges of life, &lt;strong&gt;desperation, anger, fear&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;weakness of will&lt;/strong&gt;. The world is then perceived much more through a &lt;strong&gt;filter of powerlessness and worthlessness&lt;/strong&gt;. This results in a pronounced &lt;strong&gt;emotional instability&lt;/strong&gt;. A movement between the extremes of &lt;strong&gt;control mania&lt;/strong&gt; on the one hand and &lt;strong&gt;letting oneself go&lt;/strong&gt; on the other can be experienced. In addition, these people may see themselves more as &lt;strong&gt;victims&lt;/strong&gt; and feel neglected, in dependencies, envious and embittered. The self-image is shaped by negative convictions and eventually leads to a &lt;strong&gt;loss of self-worth&lt;/strong&gt; and in extreme cases even to &lt;strong&gt;self-hatred&lt;/strong&gt;.
This chakra can also become (over)active when another chakra is overloaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-element-fire-&#34;&gt;The element fire 🔥&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chakra is associated with the element &lt;strong&gt;fire&lt;/strong&gt;. This symbolises the &lt;strong&gt;willingness to set things in motion&lt;/strong&gt;. Very well known in Kundalini Yoga is the &lt;strong&gt;breath of fire&lt;/strong&gt;, which supplies your third chakra with energy and also has a detoxifying function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-you-see-it&#34;&gt;Can you see it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sense associated with the navel chakra is &lt;strong&gt;seeing&lt;/strong&gt;. This power of seeing is linked to the &lt;strong&gt;stimulation of the sympathetic nervous system&lt;/strong&gt;.
Vision is also about visualizing personal goals and creating concrete images. In this way a sense of &lt;strong&gt;focus&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; can be created. It also stands for looking out into the world and then enables a comparison with the self-concept. Finally, vision then also creates a feeling of &lt;strong&gt;control&lt;/strong&gt;. 👁️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I consider particularly exciting here is &lt;strong&gt;spiritual vision&lt;/strong&gt;. It enables you to &lt;strong&gt;perceive the emotional-mental field that surrounds you&lt;/strong&gt; and to &lt;strong&gt;feel the energies of the people around you&lt;/strong&gt; in an intuitive way. Fascinating! 🌟&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;third_chakra.png&#34; alt=&#34;Manipura&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;main-characteristics-of-the-navel-chakra&#34;&gt;Main characteristics of the navel chakra&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit: Manipura&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Position: Area of the navel center, solar plexus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color: Yellow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element: Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological function: Self-definition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge: Shame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ego Identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I do.&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;I have the right to act.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kundalini-yoga--manipura&#34;&gt;Kundalini Yoga &amp;amp; Manipura&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manipura can also be activated, balanced and reconnected to the other equally important chakras through certain asanas from &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt;. Here you find again a list of &lt;strong&gt;exercises&lt;/strong&gt; that are especially interesting for the &lt;strong&gt;Manipura&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stretch Pose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sat Kriya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peacock position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archer Pose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fish Pose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uddiyana Bandh (Diaphragm lock)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breath of Fire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all exercises that train the abdominal muscles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general I would like to point out, as every time, that this list is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; a &amp;ldquo;panacea&amp;rdquo; and you have to &lt;strong&gt;look for yourself&lt;/strong&gt; what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t, where your &lt;strong&gt;individual possibilities and limits&lt;/strong&gt; lie! It can serve as a help, which you are welcome to try out if you feel like working on your third chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga session&lt;/strong&gt; usually different chakras are touched and activated, often with a focus. If you would like to know more about this or if you would like to book a Kundalini Yoga session with me on a specific chakra or topic, please feel free to send me an &lt;strong&gt;email&lt;/strong&gt; as usual. ✉️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my next blog post I will focus on the &lt;strong&gt;fourth chakra&lt;/strong&gt;.
To keep up to date with my current posts, I invite you to follow me on my social media channels (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;). 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal notice</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/legal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/legal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;address&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elvira Eulitz&lt;br&gt;
Im Großen Büchenfeld 24&lt;br&gt;
30453 Hannover&lt;br&gt;
Germany&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-Mail:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ruhahealing@gmail.com&#34;&gt;ruhahealing@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;responsible-for-the-content-of-this-website&#34;&gt;Responsible for the content of this website&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elvira Eulitz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;copyright&#34;&gt;Copyright&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All texts, pictures and illustrations on this website are licensed under CC BY-NC-SA 4.0 (Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International), unless otherwise stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of ruhahealing.com is for information purposes only. It can and should in no case replace medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. You should never use the information provided here as the sole source for health-related decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of ruhahealing.com does not claim to be complete, nor can the actuality, accuracy and balance of the information provided be guaranteed. Under no circumstances does it replace professional advice from a doctor or pharmacist and it may not be used as a basis for independent diagnosis and the beginning, modification or termination of a treatment of diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always consult a doctor of your choice in case of health questions or complaints!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any damage or inconvenience caused by the use or misuse of the information on ruhahealing.com, ruhahealing.com cannot be held responsible - neither directly nor indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;privacy&#34;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;general-information&#34;&gt;General Information&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a service provider Elvira Eulitz points out to the visitors of this website according to the EU data protection regulation (DSGVO) that data are collected and processed when visiting the website. This data protection declaration can be accessed by visitors to the website at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;usage-data&#34;&gt;Usage data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When visiting the website, personal data is collected from the users, which enables the use of the website (usage data). In particular, it concerns features for identification and information about the beginning, the end, the duration and the extent of the use of the website. This data is only used internally to generate access statistics and is not merged with other data. This means that it is not possible to assign the data to a specific person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elvira Eulitz may use pseudonyms to create user profiles for the purposes of advertising, market research and the demand-oriented design of the website. However, the user profiles cannot be combined with the data on the bearer of the pseudonym. The user of the website can object to the creation of a user profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to generate access statistics, the following data is collected when the website is visited: IP address, URL of the page accessed, referrer (the previous page from which reference was made to the page accessed), date and time of access, duration of access. The data collected when you visit the website will only be used internally for the stated purposes and will not be passed on to third parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. &amp;ldquo;(&amp;ldquo;Google&amp;rdquo;). The use is based on art. 6 par. 1 p. 1 lit. f. DSGVO. Google Analytics uses &amp;ldquo;cookies&amp;rdquo;, which are text files placed on the user&amp;rsquo;s computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about the use of the website, such as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser type/version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;operating system used,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referrer URL (the previously visited page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host name of the accessing computer (IP address)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time of the server request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;are usually transferred to a Google server in the US and stored there. The IP address transmitted by the browser within the framework of Google Analytics is not merged with other Google data. We have also added the code &amp;ldquo;anonymizeIP&amp;rdquo; to Google Analytics on this website. This guarantees that the IP address of the user is masked so that all data is collected anonymously. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate the use of the website, to compile reports on the website activities and to provide the website operator with further services associated with the use of the website and the Internet. The storage of cookies can be prevented by a corresponding setting of the browser software. However, we would like to point out to users that in this case they may not be able to use all functions of this website to the full extent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the collection of data generated by the cookie and related to the use of the website (including the IP address) to Google and the processing of this data by Google can be prevented by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following link: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en&#34;&gt;http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en&lt;/a&gt;. As an alternative to the browser add-on, especially for browsers on mobile devices, the collection by Google Analytics can also be prevented by clicking on 
&lt;a href=&#34;javascript:gaOptout%28%29&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. An opt-out cookie is set which prevents the future collection of the user&amp;rsquo;s data when visiting this website. The opt-out cookie is only valid in this browser and only for our website and is stored on the user&amp;rsquo;s device. If the cookies in this browser are deleted, the opt-out cookie must be set again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user can find the terms of use and data protection of Google Analytics 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://policies.google.com/?hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mentioned data are stored for 26 months. If the data is no longer required, it will be deleted immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;contact-form&#34;&gt;Contact form&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you send us enquiries via the contact form, your details from the enquiry form, including the contact data you provide there, will be stored by us for the purpose of processing the enquiry and in the event of follow-up questions. We will not pass on this data without your consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The processing of the data entered in the contact form is thus exclusively based on your consent (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a DSGVO). You can revoke this consent at any time. For this purpose, an informal notification by e-mail to us is sufficient. The legality of the data processing operations carried out up to the time of revocation remains unaffected by the revocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data entered by you in the contact form will remain with us until you request us to delete it, revoke your consent to its storage or the purpose for which it was stored ceases to apply (e.g. after your enquiry has been processed). Mandatory legal provisions - in particular retention periods - remain unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fitogram-pro-software&#34;&gt;Fitogram Pro Software&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you purchase a product through Fitogram Pro, a one-time registration is required to create a customer account, where you must provide your e-mail address, a password of your choice and your first and last name (the legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 par. 1 b) DSGVO). After you have logged in, you can delete your user account at any time.
If you create a user profile with fitogram GmbH, the data protection regulations of fitogram GmbH apply, which you can find at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fitogram.pro/en/privacy-en/&#34;&gt;https://www.fitogram.pro/en/privacy-en/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The online registration is binding and legally valid even without signature.
If you would like to book services through this form, it is necessary for the conclusion of the contract that you provide personal data which is required for the processing of the booking. We process the data you provide to process the booking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The due course fee is to be paid at the time of booking and can be paid by credit card, SEPA direct debit mandate or manual bank transfer. The payment data will be transmitted automatically. If you choose direct debit as your payment method, we can pass on your payment data to our house bank if the direct debit mandate is issued accordingly. Legal basis for the above data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. b DSGVO.
Due to commercial and tax law requirements, it is obligatory to store your address, payment and order data for a period of ten years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;objection-revocation-information-correction-blocking-deletion&#34;&gt;Objection, revocation, information, correction, blocking, deletion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user of the Ruha Healing website has the right to revoke his consent to the use of his data according to Art. 7, par. 3 of the DSGVO and to request information about the data collected in the context of the use at any time. In addition, the user has the right to request the correction, blocking or deletion of this data within the legally prescribed framework. To exercise the above rights or to declare any objection to the creation of a user profile, the user sends an e-mail to the e-mail address stated in the imprint of the website and - if necessary for his request - states his IP address and the time of access. Elvira Eulitz will then provide the requested information and arrange for the data to be corrected, blocked or deleted as far as possible. Information may also be provided electronically on request. In addition, the user has the right of appeal under Art. 77 DSGVO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elvira Eulitz acts as data protection officer of our company. Mrs. Eulitz can be reached at any time by our users by email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ruhahealing@gmail.com&#34;&gt;ruhahealing@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; if, for example, users wish to receive further information about the processing of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The second chakra</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-second-chakra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-second-chakra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After I introduced you to the power of the chakras and the first chakra in particular in my last blog post, I will now focus on the next chakra in this series: the &lt;strong&gt;sacral chakra&lt;/strong&gt;, also known as the &lt;strong&gt;sexual chakra&lt;/strong&gt;.
In Sanskrit this chakra is called &lt;strong&gt;Svadisthana&lt;/strong&gt;, where sva stands for &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;prana&amp;rdquo; and adisthana for &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;dwelling place&amp;rdquo;. Thus, in summary, the translation &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;dwelling place of the self&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; can be crystallized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sacral chakra is located in the &lt;strong&gt;region of the sexual organs&lt;/strong&gt;, at the level of the hip bones under the navel. Relevant here are the &lt;strong&gt;reproductive glands&lt;/strong&gt; (testicles, ovaries) as well as the kidneys and bladder.
&lt;strong&gt;Orange&lt;/strong&gt; is assigned to this second chakra as the color. Together with the first and third chakra it belongs to the &lt;strong&gt;lower triangle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
The main themes of this chakra are &lt;strong&gt;creativity, sexuality and reproduction, desire, sensuality as well as vitality and joy of life&lt;/strong&gt;. Basically, sensual, sexual and emotional experiences are processed in this chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More precisely this means that the sacral chakra is about the &lt;strong&gt;sensual experience of life and touching the world&lt;/strong&gt;. The soul shows itself here with its desire for joyful interaction with life, for participation in the creative play of life energy. In the experimential space of this chakra, all pure forms in the areas of life force, joy of life and emotional self-expression can be experienced. The &lt;strong&gt;deep need for the flow of life energy and living out of our creative power&lt;/strong&gt;, which is inherent in all of us, lies in the sacral chakra. It is therefore a matter of experiencing creative life energy. &lt;strong&gt;Creativity&lt;/strong&gt; can be created, for example, through words and vibrations that you produce.
This is possible, among other things, through &lt;strong&gt;sexuality&lt;/strong&gt;, because through this we can express life energy as well as needs and experience and directly touch the world. Equally important is the experience of &lt;strong&gt;emotions&lt;/strong&gt;, because these allow an intense and colourful exploration of the world and make your experience as a human being in this world real for the soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;sexual contact with another person is a first experience of merging and going beyond your own self&lt;/strong&gt;, as it comes to dissolving with and into each other. During the sexual release a state of forgetting yourself arises for a short moment, which allows you to &lt;strong&gt;experience bliss&lt;/strong&gt; by letting go and merging. &lt;strong&gt;Finity and infinity connect&lt;/strong&gt; in this moment of physical love and create a feeling of &lt;strong&gt;creative consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;. Sexuality can thus finally be used to experience the spirit. The act itself is an opportunity to live out &lt;strong&gt;creativity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of emotions is also an important aspect. In fact, &lt;strong&gt;our feelings are connected to our thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;, so thinking is not a non-emotional activity. The thoughts that you have evoke different emotions and the feelings in turn control the intensity, current and credibility of your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-element-water&#34;&gt;The element water&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sacral chakra is associated with the element water and the organs that regulate the water balance in the body. It is about the &lt;strong&gt;flow of life energy, vitality and general health&lt;/strong&gt; through an active second chakra.
Just as water moves freely, flows and has no predetermined form, so it is with feelings. These can give form to our &lt;strong&gt;habits&lt;/strong&gt;. Water has the corresponding ability to shape the earth through constant influence, and it is much more flexible than the element earth (belonging to the root chakra).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the second chakra &lt;strong&gt;works well&lt;/strong&gt;, you live in &lt;strong&gt;passion, motivation and with independent opinions&lt;/strong&gt;. The language is often characterized by sensuality, colorfulness and target orientation as well as being flexible and fluent. This is reminiscent of the above mentioned properties of water. 💦&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People with a distinct, open second chakra &lt;strong&gt;see the world in terms of feelings and desires, as a place to fulfill passions&lt;/strong&gt;. There is a passionate relationship to the liveliness itself, so that these people like to feel their liveliness. They devote themselves fully to the experience of life, live in the moment, feel joy and passion, accept their own emotions with confidence and live them out. They also like to let their sexual energy flow with devotion, enjoy it and have a sexual life marked by lust.
Furthermore, they &lt;strong&gt;rarely feel guilt or shame&lt;/strong&gt; and live &lt;strong&gt;in harmony with their true physical and emotional needs&lt;/strong&gt;, which they pursue with a healthy matter of course. &lt;strong&gt;Self-acceptance&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;self-love&lt;/strong&gt; are often well developed on this basis and &lt;strong&gt;inner balance&lt;/strong&gt; is present. 🧡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thats-tasty&#34;&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s tasty!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;sense&lt;/strong&gt; associated with this chakra is &lt;strong&gt;taste&lt;/strong&gt;. It is interesting to note that the taste in your mouth &lt;strong&gt;changes&lt;/strong&gt; when you &lt;strong&gt;experience great passion&lt;/strong&gt;. When you practice yoga, for example, you enter into a connection with the infinite, which can trigger the production of the sweet nectar Amrit and finally a change in taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;out-of-balance-&#34;&gt;Out of balance &amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the sacral chakra - just like any other chakra - can be blocked or disrupted and thus cause manifestations that can make living and acting difficult. This can happen, for example, when a person simply &lt;strong&gt;lacks sensual, sexual and emotional experiences&lt;/strong&gt; or when &lt;strong&gt;overwhelming and therefore too intense experiences&lt;/strong&gt; have been made in this area. Both extremes - undersupply as well as oversupply - lead to an imbalance or blockage.
The consequences are visible through many characteristics, for example in &lt;strong&gt;frozen emotions, feelings of guilt, boundless action and a lack of responsibility in relationships&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition, a &lt;strong&gt;reduced flow of life energy&lt;/strong&gt; is often reported and an associated reduced joy of life, including &lt;strong&gt;chronic fatigue and listlessness&lt;/strong&gt;. Due to a low level of passion, the own opinion is not very pronounced. Signs of a dysfunctional sacral chakra can also be seen in the acting out of sexuality. On the one hand there can be an &lt;strong&gt;increased loss of libido&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. a reduced desire for sexual interactions, and on the other hand there can be an &lt;strong&gt;excessive desire for sex&lt;/strong&gt;, which is more likely to be described as sexual addiction or sexual mania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, &lt;strong&gt;problems in dealing with the own emotions as well as those of the fellow human beings&lt;/strong&gt; occur here.
On a physical level, there can be problems with the &lt;strong&gt;kidneys and reproductive organs&lt;/strong&gt;. Potency problems, urinary tract infections and sexually transmitted diseases can also arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sacral_chakra.png&#34; alt=&#34;sakral chakra&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;main-characteristics-of-the-sacralsexual-chakra&#34;&gt;Main characteristics of the sacral/sexual chakra&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit: Svadisthana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Position: Genitals, one hand-width below the navel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color: Orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element: Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological function: Self-reward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge: Guilt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotional identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I feel.&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;I have the right to feel, to want.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kundalini-yoga--svadisthana&#34;&gt;Kundalini Yoga &amp;amp; Svadisthana&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As already mentioned in the first article about the chakras, the practice of Kundalini Yoga can help you to activate energies within your body and therefore also your chakras, to open and balance them. 🧘🏽‍♂️
It is important to remind yourself that the exercises can &lt;strong&gt;create a balance and establish a relationship with the energies of the other chakras&lt;/strong&gt;. With this a full functionality of the chakras can be (re)gained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of &lt;strong&gt;exercises&lt;/strong&gt; from Kundalini Yoga that can help you to work on your sacral chakra:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cobra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Butterfly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sat Kriya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cat - Cow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maha Mudra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pelvic lifting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general I would like to point out again that this list is not a &amp;ldquo;universal remedy&amp;rdquo; and &lt;strong&gt;you have to look for yourself what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t, where the individual possibilities and limits are!&lt;/strong&gt; It can serve as a help, which you are welcome to try out if you feel like working on your second chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a Kundalini Yoga session usually different chakras are touched and activated, often with a special focus. If you would like to know more about this or if you would like to book a Kundalini Yoga session with me on a specific chakra or topic, feel free to &lt;strong&gt;send me an email&lt;/strong&gt;. ✉️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my next blog post I will explain more about the &lt;strong&gt;third chakra&lt;/strong&gt; - to keep up to date with my current posts, I invite you to follow me on my social media channels (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;). 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of the chakras</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-power-of-the-chakras/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/the-power-of-the-chakras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you have already heard that the human body is equipped with different chakras. In Kundalini Yoga we always refer to the chakras and their &lt;strong&gt;particular energies&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be stimulated by the postures. But let me start from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-exactly-is-a-chakra&#34;&gt;What exactly is a chakra?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;chakra&amp;rdquo; comes from &lt;strong&gt;Sanskrit&lt;/strong&gt; and means &lt;strong&gt;wheel&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;circle&lt;/strong&gt;. It refers to energy wheels or centres in the body that are in a constant circular motion. According to this, a certain energy and power emanates from them. This energy flow refers to an interplay between physical and subtle space. These energy wheels are &lt;strong&gt;always in motion and change&lt;/strong&gt;, just as the energy itself constantly changes its frequency of oscillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; the focus is on &lt;strong&gt;8 chakras&lt;/strong&gt;. Seven of these chakras are related to the endocrine system or nerve plexuses, the eighth is associated with the magnetic field of the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;all_chakras_neutral.png&#34; alt=&#34;7 Chakras&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chakras are activated by &lt;strong&gt;Prana&lt;/strong&gt;, the power of life, and dissolve blockages that stand in the way of a &lt;strong&gt;free flow of energy&lt;/strong&gt;, or first (re-) establish a connection. The goal is always that everything is in the flow, that the energy centres can let their energies flow out. Through Kundalini Yoga this flow and the necessary &lt;strong&gt;balance&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;purification&lt;/strong&gt; of the chakras can be made possible. If there are blockages in the chakras, these can be released by practicing yoga. 🧘🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also interesting to note that the chakras &lt;strong&gt;influence perception&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;decisions&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;feelings&lt;/strong&gt;, as they can be related to different parts of the body. Furthermore, they influence your own &lt;strong&gt;projection&lt;/strong&gt; into the world. This again increases the power that emanates from them. Thus the flow of thoughts and energies in your system is also controlled by them. The human being therefore always acts and projects from the energies of the chakras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-closer-inspection-of-the-first-chakra&#34;&gt;A closer inspection of the first chakra&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chakra mentioned as the first in the series is the &lt;strong&gt;root chakra&lt;/strong&gt;. In Sanskrit it is called &lt;strong&gt;Muladhara&lt;/strong&gt;, where mula means &amp;ldquo;root&amp;rdquo; and adhara means &amp;ldquo;base&amp;rdquo;. The root chakra is located at the &lt;strong&gt;end of the spine&lt;/strong&gt; between the anus and the sexual organ. The first chakra is associated with the &lt;strong&gt;colour red&lt;/strong&gt; - see the red dot at the bottom of the figure above. It belongs together with the second and third chakra to the lower triangle.
It is also referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;foundation&lt;/strong&gt; and serves for &lt;strong&gt;survival&lt;/strong&gt;, gives &lt;strong&gt;security&lt;/strong&gt; and stands for &lt;strong&gt;habits&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;self-acceptance&lt;/strong&gt;. ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More precisely, this means that the first chakra reduces everything to the &lt;strong&gt;basics&lt;/strong&gt; and takes care of the basic needs. There is a connection to the &lt;strong&gt;element earth&lt;/strong&gt; and therefore it is responsible for all &lt;strong&gt;manifestations in the physical nature&lt;/strong&gt;.
The root chakra also serves to &lt;strong&gt;automate behaviour&lt;/strong&gt;. Consequently, this is also the place for habits and contains the strength to develop regulated habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The root chakra is assigned to the area of &lt;strong&gt;excretion&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;anus&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;large intestine&lt;/strong&gt;. Excretion here means everything from physical to emotional and mental.
In order to &lt;strong&gt;survive&lt;/strong&gt;, the human being needs a &lt;strong&gt;functioning ability to excrete&lt;/strong&gt;, which is provided by the energy of this chakra. So there is a considerable protective factor connected with the first chakra. With this knowledge you can make yourself aware that you have the ability to release negative influences (e.g. people, thoughts, environments and more) with the help of the power of the first chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite exciting to realize the fact that the own &lt;strong&gt;emotions&lt;/strong&gt; are connected to the energies in the chakras and are influenced by them. Depending on the intensity of the connection to the chakra, the different forms of emotions can be felt within yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the root chakra works well, you are connected to it and it is in harmony with the other chakras, then it gives &lt;strong&gt;purity, security, perseverance, versatility and other abilities such as steadfastness, loyalty, calmness, patience and a positive kind of intransigence&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition, there is a feeling of &lt;strong&gt;self-sufficiency&lt;/strong&gt; which arises from a &lt;strong&gt;restrained negative mind&lt;/strong&gt;. No dangers are seen and the feeling of having a foundation and of experiencing and giving support is present. Based on this, changes are implemented step by step and a &lt;strong&gt;basic level of trust&lt;/strong&gt; is a matter of course. Thus, the first chakra is also a basis for &lt;strong&gt;allowing the self-confidence to take root and grow&lt;/strong&gt;. 🌱&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time it can also lead to an &lt;strong&gt;over- or dysfunction&lt;/strong&gt; of the muladhara, which can result in various &lt;strong&gt;diseases&lt;/strong&gt;. It is about &lt;strong&gt;letting go&lt;/strong&gt; on the one hand and &lt;strong&gt;holding&lt;/strong&gt; on the other. Not being able to let go of anything can mean, for example, that toxins multiply in your body and you poison yourself. Similarly, too much clinging to things such as habits and the resulting lack of new impulses can cause you to become emotionally undersupplied. This is based on a feeling of &lt;strong&gt;fear&lt;/strong&gt;, for example of separation or poverty. More precisely, this means that there is a detachment from the inner grounding energy, i.e. a missing connection to the own root chakra.
A balance or reconnection is accordingly important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another connection exists with the &lt;strong&gt;sense of smell&lt;/strong&gt;. If you tend to hold on to and retain the toxins, you start to stink. Consequently, distance is experienced starting from other people. If the first chakra is in harmony, then you are more likely to spray a sweet body odor. What is certainly known to many is the statement that you have to be able to &amp;ldquo;smell each other&amp;rdquo;. The sense of smell also helps you to &lt;strong&gt;recognize or establish a similarity and connection to your counterpart&lt;/strong&gt; through smell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;root_chakra_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;root-chakra&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;main-characteristics-of-the-root-chakra&#34;&gt;Main characteristics of the root chakra&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit: Muladhara&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Position: at the end of the spine between anus and genitals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color: red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element: Earth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological function: Self-protection, Survival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge: Fear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physical identity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am.&amp;rdquo; / &amp;ldquo;I have the right to exist.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kundalini-yoga--muladhara&#34;&gt;Kundalini Yoga &amp;amp; Muladhara&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the practice of Kundalini Yoga every energy of the chakras can be &lt;strong&gt;transformed&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;consciousness&lt;/strong&gt; can be raised. You can use the techniques of Kundalini Yoga to use the system of the chakras for yourself.
Through the practice of Kundalini Yoga you can build a &lt;strong&gt;strong(er) connection&lt;/strong&gt; with this energy center - and all the other chakras as well. This can help you to arrive completely in your body and on earth, to live and to be in physical and emotional balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the techniques &lt;strong&gt;strengthen the central functions of the root chakra and integrate their energy into the higher chakras&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition, imbalances within the chakras can be balanced and you can get back into your center. Often it is also said that there are blockades in one or more chakras, which you can dissolve with the help of different positions as well as Kriyas or meditations from Kundalini Yoga. In other words, you may also have a missing connection to your chakra, which you can find and restore through Kundalini Yoga. This is primarily about the &lt;strong&gt;connection to Mother Earth&lt;/strong&gt;, to the &lt;strong&gt;basis of everything&lt;/strong&gt;. 🌍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you will find a list of &lt;strong&gt;positions that can harmonize and strengthen the first chakra&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crow position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chair position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Body drops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frog position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mulbandh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forward bending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kick your bottom with your feet lying on your stomach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in general I would like to point out again that this list is not a &amp;ldquo;universal remedy&amp;rdquo; and &lt;strong&gt;everyone has to look for him or herself what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t, where the individual possibilities and limits are!&lt;/strong&gt; It can serve as an aid that you are welcome to try if you feel like working on your first chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a Kundalini Yoga session, different chakras are usually touched and activated, whereby often a main focus can be identified. If you would like to know more about this or if you would like to book a Kundalini Yoga session with me on a specific chakra or topic, you are welcome to &lt;strong&gt;send me an email&lt;/strong&gt;. ✉️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my next blog post I will explain more about the &lt;strong&gt;second chakra&lt;/strong&gt; - to stay up to date about my current posts and more, I invite you to follow me on my social media channels (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ruhahealing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;). 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green diet - Day 7 &amp; conclusion</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-7-and-conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-7-and-conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-7&#34;&gt;Day 7&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For breakfast today I had the same for the last time as the previous six days. I still liked this mixture of fresh fruits very much. Nevertheless I can say that I was looking forward to the growing variety in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my work in the morning I started to cook again. For the last day this steamed vegetables were on the menu: &lt;strong&gt;broccoli, zucchini and leek&lt;/strong&gt;. This was once again a very tasty combination and I ate a big portion of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lunch_day7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lunch&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, this lunch didn&amp;rsquo;t keep me full for too long, so I prepared another &lt;strong&gt;green smoothie&lt;/strong&gt; in the afternoon. This one was very tasty again and made of cress, half a banana, lemon, grapes, apple and rosemary. This preparation of smoothies in general is something that I would like to include more in my daily diet. They are quick to prepare, very healthy and can be customized. &lt;strong&gt;Definitely a recommendation!&lt;/strong&gt; 👌🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-7-and-conclusion/gallery/Smoothie_day7.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-7-and-conclusion/gallery/Smoothie_day7_hu8e2be7f6e3e3ca6a714fff3a0146efb4_714081_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;143&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-7-and-conclusion/gallery/Smoothie_day7_after.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-7-and-conclusion/gallery/Smoothie_day7_after_hu3436930e4296c64680816a34d9f4eb95_1030935_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;143&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-7-and-conclusion/gallery/Smoothie_day7_ready.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-7-and-conclusion/gallery/Smoothie_day7_ready_hu652656409e9ec9e9c6b28f44b80e11b8_1267624_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;143&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt; 💚&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner I fried the last &lt;strong&gt;green asparagus with onion and garlic&lt;/strong&gt;. I also had the rest of today&amp;rsquo;s smoothie. All together the dinner was a really delicious meal. Peacefully I enjoyed everything in the evening sun and felt a lot of &lt;strong&gt;happiness and well-being&lt;/strong&gt; inside me. With this feeling finally the seventh and for this time last day of my green diet passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;dinner_day7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-few-final-thoughts&#34;&gt;A few final thoughts&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, I was really amazed at how quickly these 7 days went by. From the first day after the green diet I returned to eating non-green food. I was looking forward to eat other things again - &lt;strong&gt;variety&lt;/strong&gt; is just fun and I love to cook and spontaneously throw things together. I also did this &amp;ldquo;throwing together&amp;rdquo; during the green diet and found it very exciting with green food as well. I can imagine myself doing this diet form for a few more days next time, because I still have some &lt;strong&gt;other recipe ideas and ingredients&lt;/strong&gt; in my mind that would like to be realized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few days of the changeover I got really well used to this diet form and felt very &lt;strong&gt;energetic&lt;/strong&gt;. I think it is a nice way to &lt;strong&gt;eat consciously and healthily&lt;/strong&gt;. My body definitely felt &lt;strong&gt;lighter and more comfortable&lt;/strong&gt;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced the usual feeling of fullness once, because the food is simply much lighter during the green diet. Everything was very &lt;strong&gt;easy to digest&lt;/strong&gt; for me and I generally perceived my digestion as very positive.
Moreover, I did my own yoga set every morning and also practiced &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; sets on several evenings. This yoga &lt;strong&gt;supported me very well&lt;/strong&gt; and additionally energized me and provided me with &lt;strong&gt;prana&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. life energy. A &lt;strong&gt;combination of the green diet and Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; is therefore also something I can warmly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breakfast on the &amp;ldquo;day after&amp;rdquo; was more colourful again. There were green fruits, strawberries and oranges as well as oatmeal - all together as a colorful mix. Delicious! 😍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;breakfast_day_8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Breakfast&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I can say that my &amp;ldquo;relationship&amp;rdquo; to the &lt;strong&gt;color GREEN&lt;/strong&gt; has intensified to a certain extent. Green can be found in so many things and is omnipresent. The power of this color is really tangible, the energy of green has definitely &lt;strong&gt;strengthened me&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you would like to experience a green diet too!? You are more than welcome to write to me if you have further questions on this topic or if you would like to exchange ideas. 🙃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;well-by-the-way-what-does-my-dear-dietary-friend-actually-think-about-this-whole-thing&#34;&gt;Well, by the way: What does my dear dietary friend actually think about this whole thing?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When I first heard about this diet, I was very interested in trying this type of diet. Elvira asked me if I would like to join her and experience it at the same time. I read an article about it, in which they suggested to do the diet for 40 days &amp;hellip; 🤪
To be honest, I was a little worried if I could do it, but Elvira and I decided to try it for one week the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first day I was really &lt;strong&gt;excited&lt;/strong&gt; to see how my body and of course my mind would accept this challenge. I must say that it was really nice to have this experience, but after four days I started to miss more &amp;ldquo;colours&amp;rdquo; in my food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The hardest fight for me was not using salt.&lt;/strong&gt; I stopped drinking coffee two days before the diet. This was helpful to get used to the new way of eating and drinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ll do the diet again, maybe like a &lt;strong&gt;little ritual four times a year&lt;/strong&gt;. By the way, I lost some weight, but half of it came back after I returned to my normal eating habit. But losing weight was not my main goal either.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for sharing this experience with me, dear friend! 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you can gain some &lt;strong&gt;inspiration&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;courage&lt;/strong&gt; from our experiences to try out such a diet and just have a new experience for you &amp;amp; with you. Have fun with it! ✨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important note:&lt;/strong&gt;
On my blog you can find tips and insights on the topics nutrition, health, body, mind and soul. These information are primarily based on my own experiences with it, so they can in no way replace a visit to the doctor. Please read my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/legal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and consult your doctor if you have unclear symptoms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green diet - Day 5 &amp; 6</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-5-and-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-5-and-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-5&#34;&gt;Day 5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I started with my &lt;strong&gt;little yoga set&lt;/strong&gt; like every day and noticed already before that I sart this day with an unstable circulation. I know this from myself, so I took it easy and went peacefully to my yoga mat. Once there, I started with my &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; morning exercises, whereby I already noticed that I became quite warm, or rather hot. I then changed to short, airy clothes and continued with yoga, but left out some positions that require more power. I was sweating more and more, but not sweating due to the effort, but rather out of nowhere. I also had the feeling that I &lt;strong&gt;urgently needed food and water&lt;/strong&gt;. So I first drank half a liter of water and started to prepare my breakfast and cut fruit. It is still the same as the days before. 😉 Afterwards I felt much better again and I think that this what happend to me in the morning was kind of a &lt;strong&gt;detoxification process&lt;/strong&gt;. Wow - that was definitely very intense!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I had enough energy to participate in my Sunday morning yoga class. I also felt very well there and was able to gain a lot of strength and &lt;strong&gt;prana, the so-called life energy&lt;/strong&gt;, from it. I felt deep gratitude and bliss within me. 🙏🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;breakfast+water_day5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Breakfast&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the by now rather unspectacular, but always delicious breakfast, I made myself the really last &lt;strong&gt;leftovers of the mung bean dish&lt;/strong&gt; for lunch. You already know this one from the past days. It was only a small remainder, but for now it satiated me sufficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I cycled to the beach. Once there, the prepared snacks were taken out. For me these are grapes and melon. With sunshine and the sound of the sea these fresh snacks taste much better than they already do. ☀️ 🌊&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lunch_snack_picknick_day5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Beach snack&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back again from the bike trip I looked deeper into the fridge at home. There I actually found another mini leftover of the mung beans and ate it directly. Afterwards I ate some &lt;strong&gt;green olives&lt;/strong&gt; and was satisfied again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening I offered my &lt;strong&gt;online Kundalini Yoga session&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a lot of fun again and I felt really positively energized and very happy at the end of it. If you would like to participate in one of my online Kundalini Yoga classes, please register for it using the &lt;strong&gt;link at the end of this post&lt;/strong&gt;. The course on every Sunday evening is so far &lt;strong&gt;free of charge&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;open for all interested people&lt;/strong&gt;. I am looking forward to welcome you there! 🧘🏽‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-6&#34;&gt;Day 6&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my breakfast, which you probably know by now, I did my work like every day. I still felt the &lt;strong&gt;positive after-effects of yesterday&amp;rsquo;s yoga session&lt;/strong&gt; and all the healthy green food. My body has probably never received so much &lt;strong&gt;chlorophyll&lt;/strong&gt; in such a short time. 🙃 I noticed a real &lt;strong&gt;energy boost&lt;/strong&gt; and was looking forward to the recurring fruit breakfast more than usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I was very hungry again around noon. While I was cutting the vegetables, my stomach felt very unfamiliar. It was definitely not just the hunger and rather felt a little crampy in my stomach. I had the &lt;strong&gt;feeling that my body was actively working and freeing me from toxins&lt;/strong&gt; and other things like that. Even if it was a bit unpleasant, I could accept it. After a few minutes this process was over again and I prepared the following lunch for myself later: &lt;strong&gt;brussels sprouts, zucchini and green lentils with some onion and garlic&lt;/strong&gt; - all steamed together. I was really happy to finally cook brussels sprouts again, which I really love to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lunch_day6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lunch&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon I started the &lt;strong&gt;smoothie&lt;/strong&gt; production again. This time I used a little less of the cress as an ingredient, plus half a banana, a green apple, a kiwi and some of the green melon. This smoothie was definitely &lt;strong&gt;sweeter&lt;/strong&gt; than last time and therefore even more delicious. I added a few ice cubes as refreshment and enjoyed the smoothie very much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Smoothie_day6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Smoothie&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I warmed up the leftovers from lunch again for the evening and sat down for dinner in the warming evening sun. This sixth day of the green diet was again very &lt;strong&gt;beneficial and enriching for my body&lt;/strong&gt;.I felt &lt;strong&gt;strengthened and satisfied&lt;/strong&gt;. The green diet is becoming easier and easier for me and I can very well imagine to follow this diet for a longer period next time. 💚&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important note:&lt;/strong&gt;
On my blog you can find tips and insights on the topics nutrition, health, body, mind and soul. These information are primarily based on my own experiences with it, so they can in no way replace a visit to the doctor. Please read my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/legal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and consult your doctor if you have unclear symptoms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green diet - Day 3 &amp; 4</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-3-and-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-3-and-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I felt the hunger coming back in me as soon as I woke up. Thoughts of breakfast were already on my mind. I noticed that I was very much in the mood for my &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; breakfast, although it is somewhat similar to that - well, without any carbohydrates and another fruit variety. However, when I was about to eat my fresh fruit, I was happy and full again. Today I added some lemon on top. That gave my breakfast a special sour taste, which I really enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;breakfast.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Breakfast&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For early lunch I had mung beans with green lentils, served with savoy cabbage, leek and broccoli. During these green diet days I find mung beans really tasty, maybe because they satiate me a bit more in comparison! In any case, this is a personal discovery of a food that I would like to use more regularly in cooking from now on. I&amp;rsquo;ve never used mung beans to prepare anything myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve only eaten them with others. Try it out! 🙃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;brokkoli_day3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lunch&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from that, I can say on this third day that I still felt very well, despite the regular hunger. However, I think this is understandable without all the carbohydrates that are usually integrated in my meals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an early dinner I made myself a green smoothie today. I can warmly recommend that as well! I had a mixture of a special kind of cress, an apple, a kiwi, half a banana WITH peel - yes that&amp;rsquo;s allowed 😉 - and half a lime in addition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-3-and-4/gallery/green_smoothie_after.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;All mixed up&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-3-and-4/gallery/green_smoothie_after_hu7cb95bc99fc311725252d83209c15a72_1230339_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;143&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-3-and-4/gallery/green_smoothie_before.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ingerients&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-3-and-4/gallery/green_smoothie_before_hu17b2e57b1945b0ca3c14853e665fc8ca_741429_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;143&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-3-and-4/gallery/green_smoothie_ready.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ready to enjoy!&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-3-and-4/gallery/green_smoothie_ready_hu6c5f28cfb52e5ee4a64c4143e4a49817_1115228_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;143&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt; 💚&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This smoothie was really tasty, but a bit too bitter for me. Next time I&amp;rsquo;ll use some more sweet fruits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that I always leave the skin on the kiwi. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this for years. For me it tastes even more intense with the skin and remains a very tasty fruit in my opinion. This also applies to the less popular, hairy kiwis. 😉 Many of the nutrients are in or directly under the shell and by removing them your body will not even be able to enjoy these valuable ingredients. Consider this as an invitation to try one or the other fruit WITH the shell and do your body even more favours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;day-4&#34;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is &amp;ldquo;half time&amp;rdquo; - half of the green diet week is already mastered, so to speak, at least around noon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For breakfast, I guess I don&amp;rsquo;t need to say much anymore: I ate the same fresh fruit as the last days. Also today I found this again a delicious and good mixture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, today I was not as hungry as the days before. It is often said that the body has to get used to this change during the first 1-3 days. So maybe I had truly arrived at all levels since today&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I have noticed from time to time, however, are certain movements in the stomach area that seemed new to me. It felt a bit like internal cramps, but it was not really painful. I suspect detoxification processes in my body&amp;hellip; and with this thought I can accept the feeling well and let my body do its work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then at lunch I just warmed up the leftovers from yesterday. It was the mung beans with lentils, broccoli, leeks and savoy cabbage. Even today this set still tasted wonderful. But that could also be because I took this food with me on our bike trip and then enjoyed it on the picnic blanket on the beach. This way everything tastes even better, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?! ☀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lunch_beach_day4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lunch beach&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening I found myself back in the kitchen, preparing some tasty dinner for my fourth&amp;rsquo; day. This was fresh green asparagus, the remaining Pimientos de Padron and some zucchini. Everything was first steamed and at the end fried a little bit - delicious!
Ready cooked I enjoyed the food outside in the evening sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;dinner_day4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner sunset&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really felt more and more comfortable with this form of nutrition. I had a lot of energy in me and was more than happy about this decision. Thus I was looking forward to the 3 further days ahead. I will also tell you about those in my upcoming blog articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important note:&lt;/strong&gt;
On my blog you can find tips and insights on the topics nutrition, health, body, mind and soul. These information are primarily based on my own experiences with it, so they can in no way replace a visit to the doctor. Please read my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/legal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and consult your doctor if you have unclear symptoms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green diet - Day 1 &amp; 2</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-1-and-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-day-1-and-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/center&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I usually eat a lot of fresh fruit in the morning, but I generally mix it with yoghurt or porridge. But today, my first breakfast allowed me only a &lt;strong&gt;pure green fruit bowl&lt;/strong&gt;. These fruits did not really keep me full for a long time, so that I soon started to think about lunch. I bought some &lt;strong&gt;spinach&lt;/strong&gt;, because I was very much in the mood for it. I added &lt;strong&gt;zucchini&lt;/strong&gt; and a mini onion as well as some garlic (yes, these ingredients are allowed despite the missing green colour - what a blessing! 🙏🏽 ). Everything was cooked together and what can I say, it was really delicious. However, I forgot how much the leaves still lose volume during cooking. Thus the lunch portion was quite small for my big hunger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Spinach_Zucchini.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lunch&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well then, since there is no limit to the number of meals - luckily 😀 -, I started cooking again in the afternoon. I had previously soaked the &lt;strong&gt;mung beans&lt;/strong&gt; for a few hours and then boiled them up. I also added a good amount of &lt;strong&gt;green lentils&lt;/strong&gt;. I think lentils are just delicious and suitable for mung beans - from my point of view only recommendable. You can also add the lentils to the mung beans for the last 15 minutes if you want to eat them together anyway. Just make sure that you have enough water in your pot - mung beans and lentils need to have enough water to get ready. I also added &lt;strong&gt;zucchini, which were fried with some onion and garlic&lt;/strong&gt;. That is another very tasty menu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Dinner_Mungbeans.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening I did some &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt;, which felt very good for me at this moment. I could immerse myself in the Kriya and relax. My body felt fulfilled and comfortable afterwards and I was deeply grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But… maybe you can guess… I was hungry again that evening. Oh gosh, should I cook again? A view into the pantry makes my eyes stop at the &lt;strong&gt;Pimientos de Padron&lt;/strong&gt;. So I fried some of them thoroughly. This was really tasty. I also ate a few &lt;strong&gt;green olives&lt;/strong&gt;. Finally I felt filled up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Okras.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner again&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in the evening I went to bed with a little hunger, but also with a &lt;strong&gt;light and happy&lt;/strong&gt; feeling. The food during the day did me very well, I already noticed that this evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-2&#34;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The morning began as usual and I prepared my &lt;strong&gt;green fruit breakfast&lt;/strong&gt;. It was the same as yesterday, a big bowl full of delicious fresh fruit. Yammi! 🍏🍐🥝🍈&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Breakfast_day2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Breakfast&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, for today it was also clear that I had to buy more green food. Most of it was already consumed, so I planed to visit the &lt;strong&gt;local organic farm&lt;/strong&gt; in the neighboring village in the afternoon. I also decided to go to the &lt;strong&gt;food market&lt;/strong&gt; and buy some green stuff for today&amp;rsquo;s lunch. No sooner said than done. The market supplied me with leek, broccoli, green asparagus, savoy cabbage and cucumber. I also used some of these for my lunch menu. This was &lt;strong&gt;mung beans with green lentils, broccoli, leek and savoy cabbage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lunch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lunch&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon I visited the mentioned local organic farm in Portugal. This is really beautifully situated in the hinterland, surrounded by a lot of green and fertile soil. With a friend who knows the owner of the farm, we cycled there together. I picked out some of the &lt;strong&gt;delicacies of this week&amp;rsquo;s harvest&lt;/strong&gt;. Take a look! 👇🏽&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;farm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;farm&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the big glass there are &lt;strong&gt;green olives&lt;/strong&gt; from this region and in the smaller &lt;strong&gt;homemade ghee&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, this is also allowed as a small side addition in the dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards I was already looking forward to cook with all these fresh ingredients. For tonight&amp;rsquo;s dinner I prepared a &lt;strong&gt;delicious salad&lt;/strong&gt;, as you can see on the next picture. As ingredients from the farm, you can find salad, raw zucchini and some of the fresh rosemary. I also added iceberg lettuce, which I had left over, as well as cucumber and dried garden herbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;salad+olives.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition I ate some of the &lt;strong&gt;olives&lt;/strong&gt;. I mixed them with the herbs I got separately and that was a really delicious combination. I ate it all outside in the evening sun. The day ended really nice and I felt very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all I can say about these first two days that I definitely &lt;strong&gt;enjoyed them a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. It is of course a change for the body, I felt that. Nevertheless, I also noticed that the green diet was good for me. I felt pleasantly satiated and even though I ate more food than usual, I felt lighter inside than usual. I was very &lt;strong&gt;curious how the next days would work out&lt;/strong&gt;.
If you are also curious, feel free to follow me on this blog or social media, where I always share all the latest news with you. 🤩&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important note:&lt;/strong&gt;
On my blog you can find tips and insights on the topics nutrition, health, body, mind and soul. These information are primarily based on my own experiences with it, so they can in no way replace a visit to the doctor. Please read my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/legal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and consult your doctor if you have unclear symptoms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green diet project</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/green-diet-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;green-diet---what-is-that&#34;&gt;Green Diet - What is that?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among a variety of fasting cures and diets, I came across the so-called &amp;ldquo;Green Diet&amp;rdquo; in connection with Kundalini Yoga by Yogi Bhajan. The name immediately caught my attention and I wanted to learn more about it and experience it. The green diet uses the &lt;strong&gt;effect of the green substance chlorophyll&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be found in any green food. During the green diet you eat mainly green fruits and vegetables and drink a lot of water or tea. This type of diet is &lt;strong&gt;vegan&lt;/strong&gt; and is not limited in the amount of food you eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green furthermore symbolizes growth, fertility and renewal. Many of you are certainly aware that green is also the color for calmness and harmony. The associations with the color green are usually &lt;strong&gt;positive&lt;/strong&gt;. Green fruits, vegetables and other green foods are also &lt;strong&gt;beneficial to your whole organism&lt;/strong&gt; as you can read next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;effects&#34;&gt;Effects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The green diet is alkaline and thus works on your &lt;strong&gt;acid-base balance&lt;/strong&gt; with a focus on the alkaline. In doing so, you deacidify your body and start a &lt;strong&gt;detoxification process&lt;/strong&gt; in your liver, which eventually rebuilds your whole organism. In addition, your skin is cleaned and toxic mucus is removed from your liver - so it is cleaned as well. Weight loss can also be a side effect, but this is not the main focus. This and even more happens mainly due to the ingredient &lt;center&gt;✨CHLOROPHYLL.✨&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green food contains chlorophyll to varying degrees. This can have a health-promoting effect on your body due to the amount absorbed. This &lt;strong&gt;strengthens your immune system and your defences&lt;/strong&gt;. Chlorophyll is also an &lt;strong&gt;antioxidant&lt;/strong&gt; and protects your body from free radicals. Your &lt;strong&gt;magnesium and iron balance&lt;/strong&gt; is improved and your blood cells are purified and &lt;strong&gt;new blood cells&lt;/strong&gt; are formed. Chlorophyll is also known as a &lt;strong&gt;natural anti-aging agent&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, your whole body experiences an activation on a physical and mental level and can only benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-to-eat&#34;&gt;What to eat?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibilities here are definitely sufficient and it is also an interesting focus to concentrate only on green food. It is a pleasure to walk through the supermarket with this attention and be surprised by the &lt;strong&gt;green variety&lt;/strong&gt;.
I&amp;rsquo;ll list some food groups with examples here, which should be broadly available:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any green salads and leafy vegetables (e.g. rocket, lamb&amp;rsquo;s lettuce, chicory, spinach, chard, pakchoi) 🥬&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sprouts and germs (e.g. mung beans, green lentils)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;green vegetables (e.g. asparagus, okras, zucchini, broccoli, peas, green beans, spring onions, green peppers, leek, fennel and many more) 🥦&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;green fruits (e.g. limes, from the inside green melons, pears, apples, kiwis, grapes, cucumber, olives, avocado) 🥑&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oils (e.g. olive oil, pumpkin seed oil, ghee)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Herbs (e.g. nettle, wild garlic, dandelion, peppermint, lemon balm, parsley, coriander and many more) 🌿&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spices (e.g. green pepper, wasabi, dried green spices)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superfoods like wheatgrass, nettle powder, spirulina, chlorella and hemp protein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚫 Important: &lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt; salt!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-what-about-drinking&#34;&gt;And what about drinking?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water and herbal teas&lt;/strong&gt; (also green tea) are the most important things. But also &lt;strong&gt;green juices&lt;/strong&gt; and the well-known &lt;strong&gt;green smoothies&lt;/strong&gt; are allowed and a satisfying snack between meals. These are best prepared fresh. In fact, you can also drink the cooked or steamed water from your vegetables. Nothing has to be poured away. 😉 However, there are also drinks that you should &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; consume: coffee, alcohol and black tea. It makes sense to wean yourself off these drinks before you start your green diet, if you drink them at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, so much for the theory of this detoxifying, purifying diet form. I have decided to do the green diet for &lt;strong&gt;7 days&lt;/strong&gt;. Together with a friend of mine I plan to eat only green for the next seven days. Exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share the process and several of my meals on my blog with you in the coming days. Be curious and let yourself be inspired. 💫&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important note:&lt;/strong&gt;
On my blog you can find tips and insights on the topics nutrition, health, body, mind and soul. These information are primarily based on my own experiences with it, so they can in no way replace a visit to the doctor. Please read my 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/legal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and consult your doctor if you have unclear symptoms.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The essence of Kundalini Yoga</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/essence-ky/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/essence-ky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a really &lt;strong&gt;big variety of yoga forms&lt;/strong&gt; like Hatha, Ashtanga, Yin, Iyengar or Power Yoga and some more. Each Yoga form has its own &lt;strong&gt;fascination&lt;/strong&gt;. I myself feel most attracted by Kundalini Yoga, although I did a lot of Hatha Yoga for years. Nevertheless, &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga has a certain attraction&lt;/strong&gt; that I have never encountered before in yoga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yoga-in-general&#34;&gt;Yoga in general&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of yoga is generally very high and the effects of regular practice are very &lt;strong&gt;beneficial to your entire body-mind-soul system&lt;/strong&gt;. With your own yoga practice you create a &lt;strong&gt;connection&lt;/strong&gt; and go into &lt;strong&gt;relation&lt;/strong&gt; with yourself. A central word here is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;consciousness&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. With the techniques of yoga you receive practical tools to connect with your higher and finally with the &lt;strong&gt;universal consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;. You can &lt;strong&gt;explore your own dimensions&lt;/strong&gt;, depth and possibilities as a human being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-why-kundalini-yoga&#34;&gt;But why Kundalini Yoga?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it is an incredibly &lt;strong&gt;energetic&lt;/strong&gt; collection of possibilities to increase your consciousness and to work on your very individual &lt;strong&gt;energy flow&lt;/strong&gt;. You are infused with different kinds of energies and can master them with Kundalini Yoga. With the flow of energy it is quite simple: The energy is in you in one way or another anyway! But &lt;strong&gt;with the help of Kundalini Yoga you can feel, control and finally use the energy for yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. This is just amazing! 🤩&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The various exercises &lt;strong&gt;work on your glandular and nervous system&lt;/strong&gt; and strengthen it through regular practice. A strong nervous system is always and maybe especially now in the current time full of challenges an important basis. By working on your nervous system you also strengthen yourself for your life outside of yoga and that is a really valuable asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the special charm is also based on the fact that many of the exercises in Kundalini Yoga are quite special. I have never experienced many of the positions and postures in other yoga forms and can say that they touch me &lt;strong&gt;extraordinarily intensely&lt;/strong&gt;. During the exercises you can often feel where inner activity is developing, where the energy is flowing, where it is blocked and more. In addition, you &lt;strong&gt;meet yourself&lt;/strong&gt; again and again, especially when you completely devote yourself to the exercises. It is not uncommon for students to report &lt;strong&gt;special feelings and sensations&lt;/strong&gt; after the yoga sessions. That alone has something &lt;strong&gt;magic&lt;/strong&gt; for me! ✨
This also happens through the &lt;strong&gt;work on your 8 chakras&lt;/strong&gt;. The theory and meaning of the chakra knowledge is just as valuable and helpful for your own spiritual path. You&amp;rsquo;ll find blog posts with an introduction to the world of each chakra later on my website. Interested in these and other issues? You are welcome to stay up to date and follow me on social media to be informed about new blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, Kundalini Yoga gives you &lt;strong&gt;power and inspiration&lt;/strong&gt; for your development and can result in awakening your soul. This process is also called the &lt;strong&gt;awakening of the Kundalini energy&lt;/strong&gt;. 💫&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-term-kundalini&#34;&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Kundalini&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;em&gt;Kundalini&lt;/em&gt; is referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;awakening of your soul&lt;/strong&gt;. It is often mentioned that through yoga you can awaken your kundalini energy and let it rise into your higher chakras.
According to yogic understanding, this specific energy lies curled up in the lowest chakra, the muladhara, and can be made to rise through yogic practice. Then, &lt;strong&gt;through specific exercises, this powerful energy is stimulated and enabled to flow through the chakras&lt;/strong&gt; and finally reach the very top. Once there, it is said that you attain a &lt;strong&gt;state of &amp;ldquo;super-consciousness&amp;rdquo; in consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;. ✨ WOW! ✨ Does&amp;rsquo;t that sound fascinating?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you already realized how powerful Kundalini Yoga is as a whole. However, theoretical insights into how it works are not the only thing that matters. Especially important is: &lt;strong&gt;Experience it!&lt;/strong&gt; Get involved and meet your own energy system, put yourself in relation to your true identity, your &lt;strong&gt;Sat Nam&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I invite you to be part in my online Kundalini Yoga sessions. Once a week, usually Sunday evening 6pm CEST, I give &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga online live classes for free&lt;/strong&gt;. I am happy to meet you there. Feel free to sign up for it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdTnjS-7jCCpNDa8fqbtLhQ0lp9MYRzGavpt-oIq_avyIRZpw/viewform?embedded=true&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;982&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&gt;Loading…&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-such-a-class-look-like&#34;&gt;What does such a class look like?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will all - as a group and at the same time each one of us for him or herself -  tune in with the &lt;strong&gt;Adi Mantra &amp;ldquo;Ong Namo Guru Dev Namo&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. This prepares your system and connects you to your higher self. Followed by the &lt;strong&gt;protection mantra &amp;ldquo;Ad Gureh Nameh&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, we create an almost sacred space.
Then we start with the movement and your body can &lt;strong&gt;WARM UP with a few exercises&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equally important is the handling of the &lt;strong&gt;breath&lt;/strong&gt;. This is an &lt;strong&gt;indispensable connection to every life&lt;/strong&gt; and therefore very important. Through different &lt;strong&gt;PRANAYAMA techniques&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. breathing techniques, different energy states can be created and controlled. There is a wide range of pranayama exercises with different rhythms and tempos, which then have their individual influence on the body-mind-soul system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central part of a Kundalini Yoga class is the &lt;strong&gt;KRIYA&lt;/strong&gt;. The term Kriya stands for a &lt;strong&gt;series of exercises&lt;/strong&gt;. The range for these Kriyas is all-encompassing and really huge. You can find everything from very gentle to medium to very challenging Kriyas. The difference to other yoga styles such as hatha yoga is that &lt;strong&gt;many exercises are dynamic&lt;/strong&gt;. Often the position is also &lt;strong&gt;in connection with a certain breathing technique&lt;/strong&gt; like for example the energizing fire breath.  But there are also static postures, which are not really comparable with positions I know from other yoga styles. It&amp;rsquo;s a special yoga world which is worth getting to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this practice you prepare your body for the final meditation. When the Kriya is finished, you will have the opportunity for &lt;strong&gt;DEEP RELAXATION&lt;/strong&gt; before &lt;strong&gt;MEDITATION&lt;/strong&gt;. This will help your body to integrate all the experiences made in the series of exercises on a cellular level. For meditation, the possibilities are equally wide and varied. Basically it is common to distinguish between &lt;strong&gt;meditations with and without mantra&lt;/strong&gt;. At the very end we tune out with the &lt;strong&gt;song &amp;ldquo;May the long time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; and simply enjoy the flow of energy in our system. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, in Kundalini Yoga we like to chant mantras. You can open your heart and connect with the sound-flow of the mantras. If you really get involved and let the songs enter your system, you can dive deeply into yourself and feel a sense of &lt;strong&gt;well-being&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Yoga is not going to make you great. Yoga is going to make you you!” (Yogi Bhajan)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Ruha Healing</title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/post/introducing-ruha-healing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/post/introducing-ruha-healing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sat Nam&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Welcome to &lt;strong&gt;Ruha Healing&lt;/strong&gt;! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy that you&amp;rsquo;ve found my website and are interested in getting to know me and my work.
I have been practicing Yoga for many years, and especially Kundalini Yoga has hit me right in the heart. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a true treasure in it, which I can hardly wait to share with you. Finally it has happened that my heart project goes live and I can share all my ideas and services with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruha Healing deals with various topics around &lt;strong&gt;spirituality&lt;/strong&gt;, Yoga - &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; in particular, &lt;strong&gt;meditation&lt;/strong&gt;, connection to the &lt;strong&gt;soul&lt;/strong&gt; and the whole &lt;strong&gt;body-mind-soul-system&lt;/strong&gt;. I want to accompany you on your very individual journey to your inner core, your self, &lt;strong&gt;your true essence - your SAT NAM&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;importance-of-ruha-healing&#34;&gt;Importance of Ruha Healing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ruha&lt;/strong&gt; is the word for &lt;strong&gt;soul&lt;/strong&gt; in Gurmukhi, which originated from the Indian scriptures. This language is used in Kundalini Yoga for many terms and mantras. Connected with the word healing I offer you a way to your &lt;strong&gt;individual soul healing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through my work I want to give you the opportunity to &lt;strong&gt;deepen the access to your soul and to start a process of healing&lt;/strong&gt;. The human soul is often taken up by layers that arise from the outside, for example educated behavior, implanted beliefs, pressure on various levels, expectations of other people and much more. Through Kundalini Yoga your soul can be freed from all this stress and influence - step by step you can reach your true self and &lt;strong&gt;recognize you within yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. You can let things go and heal in a gentle way with this yogic tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to experience this, it is beneficial to develop a &lt;strong&gt;regular yoga practice&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;dedicate yourself&lt;/strong&gt; fully to your path. Try it out, let yourself go, start or continue your &lt;strong&gt;spiritual journey&lt;/strong&gt;. Wherever you are right now in life and in the access to your self - everything is right as it is, you have all possibilities to unfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-does-this-work&#34;&gt;How does this work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I organize live classes of &lt;strong&gt;Kundalini Yoga by Yogi Bhajan&lt;/strong&gt;, both &lt;strong&gt;online and onsite&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The live online classes can be joined from wherever you are, all you need is a good internet connection and a device such as a laptop, tablet or phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://zoom.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;meet virtually&lt;/strong&gt; but you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see and listen to my live instructions. For the best experience, I generally recommend that you also use a webcam and share your video but it is not mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onsite classes are currently paused because of the Corona virus but as soon as the situation allows it they will resume both in Portugal and Germany where I live and work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it is possible that you book a yoga course with me for yourself, a group or a special event. Feel free to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ruhahealing.com/#contact&#34;&gt;reach out to me&lt;/a&gt; to discuss any details directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I invite you to &lt;strong&gt;experience the special techniques of Kundalini Yoga&lt;/strong&gt; - with you, on your mat and &lt;strong&gt;together on the way to your Sat Nam&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover I will write blog posts and share some specific Kundalini Yoga knowledge with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-now-&#34;&gt;Start now&amp;hellip; 🧘‍♀️&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; and directly &lt;strong&gt;join my next Kundalini Yoga session online on Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll be using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://zoom.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt; for these online classes so you can join to practice Kundalini Yoga from your home or wherever you might be stucked at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you need is to put your matress at your favourite place where you have enough space to move your body, grab a cushion and blanket, prepare some drinking water and meet me online to do yoga!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course starts on &lt;strong&gt;Sunday, April 26, 6 PM CEST&lt;/strong&gt; (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://savvytime.com/converter/germany-berlin-to-ca-san-francisco-ny-new-york-city-singapore-singapore/apr-26-2020/6pm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Find your local time&lt;/a&gt;) but the Zoom meeting will open up &lt;strong&gt;20 minutes in advance&lt;/strong&gt; and I recommend to show up early as participation in this course is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is offered &lt;strong&gt;free of charge&lt;/strong&gt;. Thus I hope to do something good for you in these wild times and sweeten your Sunday a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;strong&gt;sign up for the Sunday class right here&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdTnjS-7jCCpNDa8fqbtLhQ0lp9MYRzGavpt-oIq_avyIRZpw/viewform?embedded=true&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;982&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&gt;Loading…&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stay up to date about my next courses, new blog posts and more, you can also follow me on facebook, Instagram and Twitter. I am happy to be connected with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am very happy to welcome you in my classes, to get to know you and to support you on your very own way.&lt;/strong&gt; 💚&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ruhahealing.com/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ruhahealing.com/faq/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
